<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/atom.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/atom.css" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<id>http://www.R-exams.org/</id>
	<title>R/exams</title>
	<updated>2020-09-22T09:23:27+02:00</updated>
	<subtitle>Automatic generation  and evaluation of exams. From Markdown, LaTeX and R code to standalone documents, learning management systems and live voting.</subtitle>
	
		
		<author>
			
				<name>Achim Zeileis</name>
			
			
				<email>Achim.Zeileis@R-project.org</email>
			
			
				<uri>https://eeecon.uibk.ac.at/~zeileis/</uri>
			
		</author>
	
	<link href="http://www.R-exams.org/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link href="http://www.R-exams.org/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
	<generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator>
	
    
    
		<entry>
			<id>http://www.R-exams.org/general/distancelearning/</id>
			<title>R/exams for Distance Learning: Resources and Experiences</title>
			<link href="http://www.R-exams.org/general/distancelearning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="R/exams for Distance Learning: Resources and Experiences" />
			<updated>2020-09-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Achim Zeileis</name>
					
					
						<email>Achim.Zeileis@R-project.org</email>
					
					
						<uri>https://eeecon.uibk.ac.at/~zeileis/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Resources and experiences shared by the R/exams community for supporting distance learning in different learning management systems.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.R-exams.org/general/distancelearning/">&lt;p&gt;Resources and experiences shared by the R/exams community for supporting distance learning in different learning management systems.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;R/exams for Distance Learning: Resources and Experiences&quot; src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/images/distancelearning.title.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 pandemic forced many of us to switch abruptly from our usual teaching schedules to distance learning formats. Within days or a couple of weeks, it was necessary to deliver courses in live streams or screen casts, to develop new materials for giving students feedback online, and to move assessments to online formats. This led to a sudden increase in the interest in video conference software (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://zoom.us/&quot;&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bigbluebutton.org/&quot;&gt;BigBlueButton&lt;/a&gt;, …), learning management systems (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.moodle.org/&quot;&gt;Moodle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instructure.com/canvas/&quot;&gt;Canvas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openolat.com/&quot;&gt;OpenOLAT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blackboard.com/&quot;&gt;Blackboard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilias.de/&quot;&gt;ILIAS&lt;/a&gt;, …), and - last not least - our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org&quot;&gt;R/exams&lt;/a&gt; package. Due to the flexible “one-for-all” approach, it was relatively easy for R/exams users who had been using the system for in-class materials to transition to e-learning materials. But also many new R/exams users emerged that were interested in leveraging their university’s learning management system (often Moodle) for their classes (often related to statistics, data analysis, etc.).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As distance learning will continue to play an important role in most universities in the upcoming semester, I called for sharing experiences and resources related to R/exams. Here, I collect and summarize some of the feedback from the R/exams community. The full original threads can be found on Twitter and in the R-Forge forum, respectively.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AchimZeileis/status/1292774253516001280&quot;&gt;Twitter (@AchimZeileis): After a semester of #distancelearning is before the next semester of #distancelearning…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://R-Forge.R-project.org/forum/forum.php?thread_id=34019&amp;amp;forum_id=4377&amp;amp;group_id=1337&quot;&gt;R-Forge forum: Experiences with R/exams for distance learning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Due to the increased interest in R/exams, I contributed various YouTube videos to help getting an overview of the system and to tackle specific tasks (creating exercises or online tests, summative exams, etc.). Also, the many questions asked on StackOverflow and the R-Forge forum led to numerous improvements in the software and support for various typical challenges.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;R/exams webinar @ WhyR?: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PnyCR7q4P4Q&quot;&gt;YouTube video&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/general/whyr2020/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Video tutorials: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCWDENSBdBxq-Z-hKIcLg1bA/videos&quot;&gt;YouTube channel Achim Zeileis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Questions &amp;amp; answers: &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/r-exams&quot;&gt;StackOverflow/r-exams&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://R-Forge.R-project.org/forum/forum.php?forum_id=4377&quot;&gt;R-Forge forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;But in addition to these materials that we developed, many R/exams users stepped up and also created really cool and useful materials. Especially from users in Spain came a lot of interest along with great contributions:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Jonathan Tuke (YouTube video, in English): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yQnIxwTx_PU&quot;&gt;Online tests in Canvas.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Julio Mulero (blog post, in Spanish): &lt;a href=&quot;https://elultimoversodefermat.wordpress.com/2020/03/29/uso-de-r-para-la-elaboracion-de-cuestionarios-aleatorios-en-moodle/&quot;&gt;Online tests in Moodle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Estadística útil (YouTube videos, in Spanish): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nL7iZhFJY1Y&quot;&gt;Package&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YXuFFZK1gwE&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BccEnoS2T6c&quot;&gt;First steps&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UmX-RItyyQs&quot;&gt;Single choice&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fBIdJGphxGE&quot;&gt;Written exams&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6sv71iyYV1U&quot;&gt;Moodle exams&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Pedro Luis Luque Calvo (YouTube video and blog, in Spanish): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=X6dBJmzCAzE&quot;&gt;Online tests in Blackboard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://destio.us.es/calvo/post/2020-05-01-como-crear-examenes-con-rexams-y-rmarkdown/como-crear-examenes-con-rexams-y-rmarkdown/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Kenji Sato (blog posts, in Japanese or English): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kenjisato.jp/post/2020/08/rexams-online-1/&quot;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kenjisato.jp/post/2020/08/rexams-online-2/&quot;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kenjisato.jp/post/2020/09/rexams-online-3/&quot;&gt;Part 3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://kenjisato.jp/en/post/2020/07/moodle-bordered-table/&quot;&gt;bordered tables&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;at-universität-innsbruck&quot;&gt;At Universität Innsbruck&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, we had been using R/exams extensively in our teaching for a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/general/uibk_math/&quot;&gt;blended learning approach in a Mathematics 101 course (R/exams blog)&lt;/a&gt;. The asynchronous parts of the course (screencasts, forum, self tests, and formative online tests) were already delivered through the university’s OpenOLAT learning management system. Thus, we “just” had to switch the synchronous parts of the course (lecture, tutorials, and summative written exams) to distance learning formats:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;table&gt; &lt;thead&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt; &lt;/th&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Learning&lt;/th&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Feedback&lt;/th&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Assessment&lt;/th&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/thead&gt; &lt;tbody&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Synchronous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Lecture &lt;br /&gt; Live stream&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Previously: Live quiz&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Now: Online test&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; (+ Tutorial)&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Previously: Written exam&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Now: Online exam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asynchronous&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Textbook &lt;br /&gt; Screencast&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Self test &lt;br /&gt; (+ Forum)&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Online test&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/tbody&gt; &lt;/table&gt; &lt;p&gt;The most challenging part was the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/openolat_exam/&quot;&gt;summative online exam (R/exams blog)&lt;/a&gt; but overall everything worked out reasonably ok. One nice aspect was that other colleagues profited immediately from using a similar approach for their online exams as well. Like my colleague &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lisalechner.com/&quot;&gt;Lisa Lechner&lt;/a&gt; from the Department of Political Science:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Lisa Lechner: R/exams was a life-saver during the difficult semester we faced. I used it for the statistics lecture with approx. 300 students (final online exam, but also ARSnova questions) and for a smaller course on empirical methods in political science. But even before the pandemic, R/exams increased the fairness of my final exams and reduced the time spent on evaluating results. #bestRpackage2020&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;replacing-written-exams&quot;&gt;Replacing written exams&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finding a suitable replacement for the summative written exams was not only a challenge for us. One concern that came up several times was that learning management systems like Moodle might not be reliable enough for online exams, especially if students’ internet connections were flaky. Hence, one idea that was discussed, especially with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nicebread.de/&quot;&gt;Felix Schönbrodt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://freakonometrics.github.io/&quot;&gt;Arthur Charpentier&lt;/a&gt;, was to e-mail &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/62392297/create-fillable-pdf-form-with-exams2nops&quot;&gt;fillable PDF forms (StackOverflow Q&amp;amp;A)&lt;/a&gt; to students &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/freakonometrics/status/1293985139089911820&quot;&gt;instead of relying entirely on Moodle (Twitter)&lt;/a&gt;. However, I could convince them that PDF forms would create more problems than they solve (see the linked threads above for more details):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nicebread303/status/1294213560923455489&quot;&gt;Felix Schönbrodt @nicebread303&lt;/a&gt;: We thought about doing a (pseudo-written) PDF-exam, but we are very glad that we followed @AchimZeileis advice to go for Moodle. Grading is so much easier!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Another concern is, of course, cheating, no matter which format the exams use. Many R/exams users recommended to use open-ended questions and/or more complex cloze questions forcing participants to interact with a certain randomized problem, e.g., based on a randomized data set. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://prof.beuth-hochschule.de/groemping/&quot;&gt;Ulrike Grömping&lt;/a&gt; reports, this can also be combined with online proctoring for moderately-sized exams.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://R-Forge.R-project.org/forum/forum.php?thread_id=34019&amp;amp;forum_id=4377&amp;amp;group_id=1337&quot;&gt;Ulrike Grömping (R-Forge)&lt;/a&gt;: I have also run online exams via Moodle in real time, supervised in a video conference […]. And I have not used auto correction, but have asked questions that also require free text answers from students (text fields with arbitrary correct answer of (e.g.) 72 characters in a cloze exercise). Of course, the solutions support my manual correction process.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Other approaches to tackling this problem can be found in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://R-Forge.R-project.org/forum/forum.php?thread_id=34019&amp;amp;forum_id=4377&amp;amp;group_id=1337&quot;&gt;R-Forge thread&lt;/a&gt;, see e.g., the contribution by Niels Smits.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;moodle-vs-other-learning-management-systems&quot;&gt;Moodle vs. other learning management systems&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;While overall there is a lot of heterogeneity in the learning management systems that the R/exams community uses, Moodle is clearly the favorite. Moodle quizzes also have their quirks but they are surprisingly flexible and can be used at various levels.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LinXEric/status/1300750949368164352&quot;&gt;Eric Lin @LinXEric&lt;/a&gt;: I use #rexams extensively, have been for years. I used to do paper exams. Now, with distance learning, I’m serving up exams, quizzes, entry ticket questions, exit ticket questions, all using a #rexams with #moodle.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Especially, the cloze question format is popular, allowing to combine multiple-choice, single-choice, numeric, and string items.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://R-Forge.R-project.org/forum/forum.php?thread_id=34019&amp;amp;forum_id=4377&amp;amp;group_id=1337&quot;&gt;Rebecca Killick (R-Forge)&lt;/a&gt;: We moved to using this exclusively for our undergraduate quizzes in the summer of 2019 and this served us well when COVID-19 hit. We are now expanding our online assessment using R/exams. We mainly use cloze questions with randomization.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;See also the tweet by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/emilopezcano/status/1292955475579932672&quot;&gt;Emilio L. Cano @emilopezcano&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Of course, other learning management systems are also very powerful with Blackboard and Canvas probably being second and third in popularity. The OpenOLAT system, also used at our university, is less popular but in various respects even more powerful than Moodle. The support of the QTI 2.1 standard (question and test interoperability) allows to specify a complete exam, including random selection of exercises, randomized order of questions, and flexible cloze questions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;collaborating-with-colleagues&quot;&gt;Collaborating with colleagues&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;One design principle of R/exams is that each exercise is a separate file. The motivation behind this is to make it easy to distribute work on a question bank among a larger group before someone eventually compiles a final exam from this question bank. Hence it’s great to see that various R/exams users report that they work on the exercises together with their colleagues, e.g., &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AchimZeileis/status/1292774253516001280&quot;&gt;Fernando Mayer @fernando_mayer on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ilapros/status/1292825732897476611&quot;&gt;Ilaria Prosdocimi @ilapros&lt;/a&gt;: used by me and colleagues in Venice for about 500 exams via Moodle (in different basic stats courses). Mostly single choice and numeric questions. After some initial learning it worked perfectly and made the whole exam writing much easier.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;For facilitating their collaboration, the group around Fernando Mayer has even created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://shiny.leg.ufpr.br/fernandomayer/rexams/&quot;&gt;ShinyExams interface (in Portuguese)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;statistics--data-science-vs-other-fields&quot;&gt;Statistics &amp;amp; data science vs. other fields&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is not unexpected that the majority of the R/exams community employs the system for creating resources for teaching statistics, data science, or related topics. See the tweets and posts by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/FDechterenko/status/1293500357046403072&quot;&gt;Filip Děchtěrenko @FDechterenko&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BrettPresnell/status/1308209477687152641&quot;&gt;@BrettPresnell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/statsgen/status/1292952412206972928&quot;&gt;Emi Tanaka @statsgen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/visnut/status/1273445677482119168&quot;&gt;Dianne Cook @visnut&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://stuartlee.org/2020/06/17/teaching-during-a-pandemic/&quot;&gt;Stuart Lee&lt;/a&gt;. In many cases such courses are for students from other fields, such as pharmacy as reported by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/faolmath/status/1292879192854601728&quot;&gt;Francisco A. Ocaña @faolmath&lt;/a&gt; or biology as reported by:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/OwenPetchey/status/1284062358709641217&quot;&gt;@OwenPetchey&lt;/a&gt;: The Data Analysis in Biology course at University of Zurich, with 300 students this spring, used this fantastic resource to author its final exams, with upload to OLAT.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;However, there is also a broad diversity of other fields/topics, e.g., international finance and macroeconomics (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/kamromero/status/1292782321075130368&quot;&gt;Kamal Romero @kamromero&lt;/a&gt;), applied economics and accounting (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LinXEric/status/1300750949368164352&quot;&gt;Eric Lin @LinXEric&lt;/a&gt;), econometrics (Francisco Goerlich), linguistics (Maria Paola Bissiri), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/general/uibk_soilmechanics/&quot;&gt;soil mechanics&lt;/a&gt; (Wolfgang Fellin), or programming (John Tipton).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;going-forward&quot;&gt;Going forward&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;All the additions, improvements, and bug fixes in R/exams that were added over the last month are currently only available in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://R-Forge.R-project.org/R/?group_id=1337&quot;&gt;development version of R/exams 2.4-0 on R-Forge&lt;/a&gt;. The plan is to also release this version to CRAN in the next weeks.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Another topic, that will likely become more relevant in the next months as well, is the creation of interactive self-study materials outside of learning-management systems, e.g., as part of an online tutorial. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sunymaritime.edu/faculty/science/debbie-yuster&quot;&gt;Debbie Yuster&lt;/a&gt; nicely describes such a scenario:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://R-Forge.R-project.org/forum/forum.php?thread_id=34019&amp;amp;forum_id=4377&amp;amp;group_id=1337&quot;&gt;Debbie Yuster (R-Forge)&lt;/a&gt;: I plan to use R/exams to maintain source files for “video quizzes” students will take after they watch lecture videos asynchronously in my Introduction to Data Science course. Instructors at different universities will be using these videos (created by the curriculum author), and I will distribute the quizzes to interested faculty, each of whom may have a different preferred delivery mode. I’ll be giving the quizzes through my LMS (Canvas), while others may administer the quizzes in learnr, or use a different LMS. With R/exams, I can maintain a single source, and instructors can convert the quizzes into their preferred format.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;p&gt;Two approaches that are particularly interesting are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rstudio/learnr&quot;&gt;learnr (RStudio)&lt;/a&gt;, that uses R/Markdown with shiny, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/psyteachr/webex&quot;&gt;webex (psyTeachR project)&lt;/a&gt;, that uses more lightweight R/Markdown with some custom Javascript and CSS. Some first proof-of-concept code is avaiable for a &lt;a href=&quot;https://R-Forge.R-project.org/forum/forum.php?thread_id=34001&amp;amp;forum_id=4377&amp;amp;group_id=1337&quot;&gt;learnr interface (R-Forge)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/62315622/using-r-exams-in-bookdown-document-especially-for-html-output&quot;&gt;integrating webex exercises in Markdown documents (StackOverflow Q&amp;amp;A)&lt;/a&gt; but more work is needed to turn this into full R/exams interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
			
				<category term="general" />
			
			
				<category term="R" />
			
				<category term="exams" />
			
				<category term="exams2moodle" />
			
				<category term="exams2canvas" />
			
				<category term="exams2openolat" />
			
				<category term="exams2blackboard" />
			
			<published>2020-09-22T00:00:00+02:00</published>
		</entry>
	
    
    
		<entry>
			<id>http://www.R-exams.org/general/uibk_soilmechanics/</id>
			<title>Transitioning a Soil Mechanics Course to R/exams</title>
			<link href="http://www.R-exams.org/general/uibk_soilmechanics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Transitioning a Soil Mechanics Course to R/exams" />
			<updated>2020-08-31T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Achim Zeileis</name>
					
					
						<email>Achim.Zeileis@R-project.org</email>
					
					
						<uri>https://eeecon.uibk.ac.at/~zeileis/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Experiences with transitioning to R/exams for multiple automated and randomized online exams in a soil mechanics course at Universität Innsbruck (UIBK).</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.R-exams.org/general/uibk_soilmechanics/">&lt;p&gt;Experiences with transitioning to R/exams for multiple automated and randomized online exams in a soil mechanics course at Universität Innsbruck (UIBK).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Transitioning a Soil Mechanics Course to R/exams&quot; src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/images/uibk_soilmechanics.title.svg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Guest post by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uibk.ac.at/geotechnik/staff/wolfgang_fellin.html&quot;&gt;Wolfgang Fellin&lt;/a&gt; (Universität Innsbruck, Division of Geotechnical and Tunnel Engineering).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our exercises in soil mechanics are attended by about 120 students every year. Students receive their grades based on a final exam, with a multiple-choice part and additional small exercises with calculations. Due to the COVID-19 restrictions we were forced to switch from the written exams to online exams at rather short notice, for which we decided to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org&quot;&gt;R/exams&lt;/a&gt; to randomize the exercises. The possibility that the exercises produced can be used in the following (hopefully COVID-free years) as part of a blended learning course made the decision for the (not so small) effort to switch to R/exams easy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;transition-of-multiple-choice-exercises&quot;&gt;Transition of multiple-choice exercises&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;To leverage the about 100 multiple-choice exercises from our old question pool, we had to convert them to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/intro/dynamic/&quot;&gt;R/exams format&lt;/a&gt;. The pool was stored in a MySQL data base including LaTeX text for the questions, answer alternatives, images for some exercises (in EPS format) and some additional meta-information regarding the topic category and the difficulty. Due to the standardized format of the question pool - and the kind support by Achim Zeileis and Christiane Ernst - it was possible to extract all questions, embed them into the same template for R/LaTeX questions (.Rnw), and convert all EPS figures to both SVG and PDF format. A typical example is shown below (in a screen shot from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openolat.com/&quot;&gt;OpenOLAT&lt;/a&gt;, the learning management system at UIBK).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-08-31-uibk_soilmechanics//grundwasser-1-068.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-08-31-uibk_soilmechanics//grundwasser-1-068.png&quot; alt=&quot;grundwasser-1-068.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The corresponding R/LaTeX exercise file is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-08-31-uibk_soilmechanics//grundwasser-1-068.Rnw&quot;&gt;grundwasser-1-068.Rnw&lt;/a&gt; which we also converted to R/Markdown for this blog post: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-08-31-uibk_soilmechanics//grundwasser-1-068.Rmd&quot;&gt;grundwasser-1-068.Rmd&lt;/a&gt;. Both rely on the corresponding image file being available in the same directory or a sub-directory. Different graphics formats are used for different exam output formats: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-08-31-uibk_soilmechanics//image68_1.svg&quot;&gt;image68_1.svg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-08-31-uibk_soilmechanics//image68_1.pdf&quot;&gt;image68_1.pdf&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-08-31-uibk_soilmechanics//image68_1.eps&quot;&gt;image68_1.eps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Essentially, the exercises consist of:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;some R code for including the right graphics file (SVG vs. PDF) depending on the type of output format (HTML vs. PDF),&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;the (static) question text and answer alternatives in LaTeX format,&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;meta-information including &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exextra&lt;/code&gt; tags for our custom topic category and difficulty level,&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exshuffle&lt;/code&gt; tag is used for randomly subsampling the available answer alternatives.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;new-numeric-exercises&quot;&gt;New numeric exercises&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;While the subsampling approach in the multiple-choice exercises provides a certain level of randomization, I wanted to set up new numeric exercises in which all students have to calculate the correct solution(s) based on their personalized parameters. Therefore, I set up new numeric exercises in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cloze&lt;/code&gt; format where several quantities have to be computed based on the same question text. A typical example is shown below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-08-31-uibk_soilmechanics//num-setzung-1-steinbrenner.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-08-31-uibk_soilmechanics//num-setzung-1-steinbrenner.png&quot; alt=&quot;num-setzung-1-steinbrenner.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Again, the corresponding exercise files are available as: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-08-31-uibk_soilmechanics//num-setzung-1-steinbrenner.Rnw&quot;&gt;num-setzung-1-steinbrenner.Rnw&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-08-31-uibk_soilmechanics//num-setzung-1-steinbrenner.Rmd&quot;&gt;num-setzung-1-steinbrenner.Rmd&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt; And the graphics files are: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-08-31-uibk_soilmechanics//steinbrenner_fdmt.svg&quot;&gt;steinbrenner_fdmt.svg&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-08-31-uibk_soilmechanics//steinbrenner_fdmt.pdf&quot;&gt;steinbrenner_fdmt.pdf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Despite being a newcomer to both R and R/exams, setting up these exercises was quite easy because I have been using MATLAB for a long time and could quickly grasp basic R code. Also the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/&quot;&gt;exercise templates&lt;/a&gt; available online helped as did the friendly e-mail support by Achim for resolving many of the small “details” along the way.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;exam-implementation&quot;&gt;Exam implementation&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Following the R/exams tutorial on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/openolat_exam/&quot;&gt;summative online exams in OpenOLAT&lt;/a&gt; I prepared the online exam using the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2openolat()&lt;/code&gt; function. The R code I used along with a couple of comments is provided below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;## load package library(&amp;quot;exams&amp;quot;) ## exercises for the exam ## (the actual exam had 16 exercises overall, not just 2) exm &amp;lt;- c(&amp;quot;grundwasser-1-068.Rnw&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;num-setzung-1-steinbrenner.Rnw&amp;quot;) ## date used as seed and file name dat &amp;lt;- 20200528 set.seed(dat) rxm &amp;lt;- exams2openolat(exm, edir = &amp;quot;/path/to/exercise/folder/&amp;quot;, n = 200, ## number of random versions for each exercise name = paste(&amp;quot;BmGb1-Onlinetest&amp;quot;, dat, sep = &amp;quot;_&amp;quot;), points = 1, ## all exercises yield 1 point cutvalue = 8, ## threshold for passing the exam ## evaluation rule for multiple-choice exercises (standalone and within cloze): ## every wrong answer cancels a correct answer mchoice = list(eval = exams_eval(partial = TRUE, negative = FALSE, rule = &amp;quot;true&amp;quot;)), cloze = list(eval = exams_eval(partial = TRUE, negative = FALSE, rule = &amp;quot;true&amp;quot;)), solutionswitch = FALSE, ## do not show full solution explanation maxattempts = 1, shufflesections = TRUE, ## sequence of exercises is shuffled randomly navigation = &amp;quot;linear&amp;quot;, ## disable switching back and forth between exercises duration = 120, ## 2 hours stitle = &amp;quot;Exercise&amp;quot;, ## section title (for group of exercises) ititle = &amp;quot;Question&amp;quot; ## item title (for individual exercises) )&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;challenges-and-outlook&quot;&gt;Challenges and outlook&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;The main problem by producing randomized numeric examples was to find limits for the input so that the output is physically reasonable. Especially for newly created exercises, it is absolutely necessary that other colleagues act as test calculators, such that errors can be detected before students find them in their exams. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/stresstest/&quot;&gt;stress testing&lt;/a&gt; facilities in R/exams can also help.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since the course will continue being online in 2020/21 due to ongoing COVID-19 restrictions, I use R/exams now also for the practice exercises which students have to calculate during the semester. Thus, I produced about 70 new exercises, which are offered in OpenOLAT in 12 weekly online tests. After COVID-19 I will use these examples as addition to written ones, where longer and more complex task could be trained.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
			
				<category term="general" />
			
			
				<category term="R" />
			
				<category term="exams" />
			
				<category term="exams2openolat" />
			
			<published>2020-08-31T00:00:00+02:00</published>
		</entry>
	
    
    
		<entry>
			<id>http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/openolat_exam/</id>
			<title>Summative Online Exams with R/exams and OpenOLAT</title>
			<link href="http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/openolat_exam/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Summative Online Exams with R/exams and OpenOLAT" />
			<updated>2020-05-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Achim Zeileis</name>
					
					
						<email>Achim.Zeileis@R-project.org</email>
					
					
						<uri>https://eeecon.uibk.ac.at/~zeileis/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Tutorial for conducting online exams generated by R/exams in OpenOLAT, including strategies to prevent cheating such as extended randomization, linear navigation, and a sworn declaration prior to the exam.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/openolat_exam/">&lt;p&gt;Tutorial for conducting online exams generated by R/exams in OpenOLAT, including strategies to prevent cheating such as extended randomization, linear navigation, and a sworn declaration prior to the exam.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Summative Online Exams with R/exams and OpenOLAT&quot; src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/images/openolat_exam.title.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;The development version of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org&quot;&gt;R/exams&lt;/a&gt; package has recently been extended to support a few more strategies for helping to prevent cheating in summative online exams conducted remotely in the learning management system &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openolat.com/?lang=en&quot;&gt;OpenOLAT&lt;/a&gt;. Namely, the questions in an exam can now be presented in random order while employing a “linear” navigation, i.e., disallowing to switch back and forth between the questions. While this is certainly also a bit of a nuisance for “honest” and well-prepared students who are used to starting an exam with those exercises they feel most comfortable with, it should be much more of a hurdle for students trying to cheat. In this scenario only 1 in n students on average is working on a given (type of) exercise when there are n questions (or rather sections of question pools).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Admittedly, this is still a rather weak protection against cheating compared to state-of-the-art online proctoring methods, e.g., by means of video conferencing tools. However, with several hundred participants per exam, we felt that we would (a) exclude too many students without a suitable webcam and broadband internet connection, and (b) the risk of unexpected short-term problems with the video conferencing software for individual students would be too high. Therefore, we have decided to rely only on the following strategies:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;Students have to fill in a sworn declaration stating that they are doing the exam alone with only the tools allowed. This is not only important for legal reasons but even more so for priming the students to be honest right before the exam.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;In each section of exercises, there is a sufficient amount of random variation employing the “usual” randomization provided by R/exams.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Additionally, the individual order of exercises is fixed to a particular random sequence by OpenOLAT.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;p&gt;The results from semi-summative mid-term exams suggest that the strategies work reasonably well albeit leading to slightly better results compared to previous semesters (suggesting that cheating might be more prevalent than for classical in-class written exams). Nevertheless, we felt that we would stick to these strategies for the summative final exams later this month - and not employ more severe strategies such as video conferencing or simply increasing the workload or making exercises more difficult.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Note that Strategy 3 requires at least R/exams version 2.4-0 which is the development version on R-Forge at the time of writing. Thus, if you want to follow the steps below, please install this version before:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;install.packages(&quot;exams&quot;, repos = &quot;http://R-Forge.R-project.org&quot;) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;video-tutorial&quot;&gt;Video tutorial&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;A step-by-step video tutorial is available on YouTube at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hRE9SGA1F7U&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hRE9SGA1F7U&lt;/a&gt;. This not only shows how to generate the learning resources using the strategies outlined above, it also goes through the entire OpenOLAT import and configuration. Specifically, this includes visibility rules and time limits for the different components of the exam.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hRE9SGA1F7U&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-05-12-openolat_exam/youtube.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenOLAT import and configuration&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;sworn-declaration&quot;&gt;Sworn declaration&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Both for legal reasons and for priming the students to be honest, they have to sign a sworn declaration stating that they do the exam alone using only allowed tools. Technically, this is implemented by an online test with one single-choice item where they can only say “Yes”. Only when signing the declaration in this way, students can see the actual online exam.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As the declaration is also just an online test, the corresponding learning resource for OpenOLAT can be easily generated with R/exams’ &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2openolat()&lt;/code&gt; function. The “exercise” file with the text employed at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uibk.ac.at/&quot;&gt;Universität Innsbruck&lt;/a&gt; is available both in R/Markdown and R/LaTeX format and both in English &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-05-12-openolat_exam/declaration.Rmd&quot;&gt;[Rmd]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-05-12-openolat_exam/declaration.Rnw&quot;&gt;[Rnw]&lt;/a&gt; and in German &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-05-12-openolat_exam/eidesstatt.Rmd&quot;&gt;[Rmd]&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-05-12-openolat_exam/eidesstatt.Rnw&quot;&gt;[Rnw]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The ZIP archive containing the learning resource in QTI 2.1 XML format (Question &amp;amp; Test Interoperability standard) for import into OpenOLAT can be generated with:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;library(&quot;exams&quot;) exams2openolat(&quot;declaration.Rmd&quot;, n = 1, name = &quot;R-exams-declaration&quot;, points = 1, maxattempts = 0, cutvalue = 1, solutionswitch = FALSE, schoice = list(enumerate = FALSE), stitle = &quot;Sworn declaration&quot;, ititle = &quot;Declaration form&quot;, adescription = &quot;&quot;, sdescription = &quot;&quot;) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is only &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n = 1&lt;/code&gt; version of the declaration because it is not random and it can be passed (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cutvalue&lt;/code&gt;) when correctly signing the only exercise (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;points&lt;/code&gt;). Moreover, the code sets a couple above of titles, descriptions, and styles.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;randomized-exam&quot;&gt;Randomized exam&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;First, we can leverage the usual R/exams toolbox to create an exam with four exercises where each exercise actually comes from a pool of different exercise templates, and each individual exercise is the result of some random shuffling, sampling, etc. To make this demo exam easily reproducible we only employ exercises that are readily available as part of the package. Hence, the resulting exam can illustrate the basic idea but clearly the exercises would be too different (both regarding form and content) for an actual exam.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;exm &amp;lt;- list( &quot;Geography&quot; = c(&quot;capitals.Rmd&quot;, &quot;swisscapital.Rmd&quot;, &quot;switzerland.Rmd&quot;), &quot;Graphics&quot; = c(&quot;boxplots.Rmd&quot;, &quot;scatterplot.Rmd&quot;), &quot;Inference&quot; = c(&quot;ttest.Rmd&quot;, &quot;anova.Rmd&quot;), &quot;Derivatives&quot; = c(&quot;deriv2.Rmd&quot;, &quot;hessian.Rmd&quot;) ) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thus, the first exercise would be a randomly selected exercise from the three templates in geography (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/capitals/&quot;&gt;capitals&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/swisscapital/&quot;&gt;swisscapital&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/switzerland/&quot;&gt;switzerland&lt;/a&gt;). Similarly, the subsequent topics are graphics (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/boxplots/&quot;&gt;boxplots&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/scatterplot/&quot;&gt;scatterplot&lt;/a&gt;), inference (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/ttest/&quot;&gt;ttest&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/anova/&quot;&gt;anova&lt;/a&gt;), and derivatives (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/deriv2/&quot;&gt;deriv2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/hessian/&quot;&gt;hessian&lt;/a&gt;) with some random variation within each topic/section.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Then, we can draw &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n = 50&lt;/code&gt; random exams from this specification (which we would usually do if we had around 50 participants in the exam), specifying several further options:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;set.seed(2020-05-11) exams2openolat(exm, n = 50, name = &quot;R-exams-OpenOLAT&quot;, points = 1, maxattempts = 0, cutvalue = 2, solutionswitch = FALSE, duration = 60, shufflesections = TRUE, navigation = &quot;linear&quot;, stitle = names(exm), ititle = &quot;Question&quot;, adescription = &quot;&quot;, sdescription = &quot;&quot;) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Specifically, we fix the maximum &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;duration&lt;/code&gt; to 60 minutes, tell OpenOLAT to shuffle the order of the four sections/topics in the exam (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;shufflesections&lt;/code&gt;) and to fix the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;navigation&lt;/code&gt; to be linear. In order to help students to see the topics of the exercises that are still to come (without giving away too much detail) we label the section titles with the four topics from above.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;What the resulting online exam looks like and how it can be configured further within OpenOLAT is shown in detail in the video tutorial on YouTube already mentioned above. More information regarding R/exams for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/elearning/&quot;&gt;e-learning with OpenOLAT (and Moodle)&lt;/a&gt; is provided in another tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
			
				<category term="tutorials" />
			
			
				<category term="exams2openolat" />
			
				<category term="e-learning" />
			
				<category term="exam" />
			
				<category term="R" />
			
			<published>2020-05-11T00:00:00+02:00</published>
		</entry>
	
    
    
		<entry>
			<id>http://www.R-exams.org/general/cran_release_236/</id>
			<title>New R/exams Version: TinyTeX, Fixing Parameters and Random Seeds, and More</title>
			<link href="http://www.R-exams.org/general/cran_release_236/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New R/exams Version: TinyTeX, Fixing Parameters and Random Seeds, and More" />
			<updated>2020-04-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Achim Zeileis</name>
					
					
						<email>Achim.Zeileis@R-project.org</email>
					
					
						<uri>https://eeecon.uibk.ac.at/~zeileis/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>New minor releases of the R/exams package to CRAN with many enhancements including TinyTeX support and extended control over the random variation in dynamic exercises through fixed parameters or custom random seeds.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.R-exams.org/general/cran_release_236/">&lt;p&gt;New minor releases of the R/exams package to CRAN with many enhancements including TinyTeX support and extended control over the random variation in dynamic exercises through fixed parameters or custom random seeds.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;New R/exams Version: TinyTeX, Fixing Parameters and Random Seeds, and More&quot; src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/images/cran236.title.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;New versions of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/&quot;&gt;R/exams&lt;/a&gt; package (2.3-5 and 2.3-6) have been released on the Comprehensive R Archive Network at &lt;a href=&quot;https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=exams&quot;&gt;https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=exams&lt;/a&gt;. The second update was necessitated by more thorough checks for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pandoc&lt;/code&gt; availability on Solaris and OS X. In the next days binary Windows and OS X packages should also become available. The development version of the package is now version 2.4-0 on R-Forge at &lt;a href=&quot;http://R-Forge.R-project.org/R/?group_id=1337&quot;&gt;http://R-Forge.R-project.org/R/?group_id=1337&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;tinytex-support&quot;&gt;TinyTeX support&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;R/exams users that want to produce PDF output, e.g., via &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2pdf()&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2nops()&lt;/code&gt;, need to install LaTeX for rendering the exercises. Especially for users that do not write LaTeX documents themselves (but only Markdown instead) it is now much easier to install a lightweight LaTeX distribution thanks to the wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;https://yihui.org/tinytex/&quot;&gt;TinyTeX&lt;/a&gt; package by Yihui Xie. All that needs to be done is:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;install.packages(&quot;tinytex&quot;) tinytex::install_tinytex() &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;The latter installs the TinyTeX distribution and the former makes the R interface available. After that it is recommended to run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2nops()&lt;/code&gt; once:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;exams2nops(c(&quot;swisscapital.Rmd&quot;, &quot;deriv2.Rmd&quot;)) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;This takes a while because some additional LaTeX packages will be downloaded and installed automatically. Running the same command a second time will be much faster because then all required LaTeX packages will already be available.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tinytex&lt;/code&gt; R package is installed, the default is to compile PDF exams with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tinytex::latexmk()&lt;/code&gt;; otherwise &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tools::texi2dvi()&lt;/code&gt; is used (which does not offer automatic LaTeX package installation). If the latter should be used even when &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;requireNamespace(&quot;tinytex&quot;)&lt;/code&gt; is true, then &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;options(exams_tex = &quot;tools&quot;)&lt;/code&gt; can be set (instead of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams_tex = &quot;tinytex&quot;&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;fixing-parameters-and-seeds&quot;&gt;Fixing parameters and seeds&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;One frequent feature request for R/exams was to reduce the amount of random variation in exams even if the underlying exercise templates offer more flexibility. Application cases are where teachers want to control each randomly selected exercise in a quiz or exam manually. To address this, two mechanisms are provided now:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;Some of the parameters that would usually be sampled randomly can be temporarily fixed (on the fly) by using the new function &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;expar()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Several &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2xyz()&lt;/code&gt; interfaces gained a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;seed&lt;/code&gt; argument with which dedicated random seeds can be selected per exercise.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;fixing-parameters&quot;&gt;Fixing parameters&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first feature is of interest, for example, if computing the solution becomes harder when a certain parameter increases or takes a particular value. The new function &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;expar()&lt;/code&gt; allows to fix such parameters on the fly if they are defined in the first code chunk of the exercise. For example&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;expar(&quot;deriv.Rmd&quot;, a = 1, c = 0) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;generates a temporary file where the parameters &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;c&lt;/code&gt; of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/deriv/&quot;&gt;deriv&lt;/a&gt; exercise are fixed to the values &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;0&lt;/code&gt;, respectively. The result can then be processed by all &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2xyz()&lt;/code&gt; interfaces “as usual”, e.g.:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;exams2html(c( expar(&quot;deriv.Rmd&quot;, a = 1, c = 0), &quot;deriv.Rmd&quot; )) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;A potential caveat is that &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;expar()&lt;/code&gt; either needs the exercise file to be available locally in the current working directoy or with the full path. It does not work with the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;edir&lt;/code&gt; argument of subsequent &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2xyz()&lt;/code&gt; calls.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;fixing-seeds&quot;&gt;Fixing seeds&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2xyz()&lt;/code&gt; interfaces now support setting &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;seed&lt;/code&gt;s for each individual exercise in an exam to enable custom exercise selection (e.g., when only putting together a single exam). Currently, this is only supported in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;xexams()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2pdf()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2html()&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2nops()&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2blackboard()&lt;/code&gt;. Other interfaces will follow, though.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thus, using this feature, teachers can try a few random seeds for a given exercise until they get a variant they like. Then they do the same with the next exercise etc. At the end all exercises and all seeds are collected and passed on in this form: &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2xyz(c(exercise1, exercise2, ...), seed = c(seed1, seed2, ...))&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Moreover, in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2xyz()&lt;/code&gt; interfaces that support setting seeds, the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;file&lt;/code&gt; argument can now also be a matrix (rather than a vector or list). This enables customization of the exact selection of exercises in each exam. In the example below we use exactly the same random replication of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/deriv/&quot;&gt;deriv&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/tstat/&quot;&gt;tstat&lt;/a&gt; exercises, respectively, but permute their order. The final exercise is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/ttest/&quot;&gt;ttest&lt;/a&gt; in both cases but with different seeds.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;f &amp;lt;- rbind( c(&quot;deriv.Rmd&quot;, &quot;tstat.Rmd&quot;, &quot;ttest.Rmd&quot;), c(&quot;tstat.Rmd&quot;, &quot;deriv.Rmd&quot;, &quot;ttest.Rmd&quot;) ) s &amp;lt;- rbind( c(123, 321, 111), c(321, 123, 222) ) exams2html(f, seed = s) browseURL(Sys.glob(&quot;plain*.html&quot;)[1]) browseURL(Sys.glob(&quot;plain*.html&quot;)[2]) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;written-exams-nops&quot;&gt;Written exams (NOPS)&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;The tools for written &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/exams2nops&quot;&gt;NOPS exams&lt;/a&gt; that can be automatically scanned and evaluated have been enhanced.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Several users were kind enough to provide new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/nops_language/&quot;&gt;language support&lt;/a&gt;: Korean (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ko&lt;/code&gt;, 정세원), Japanese (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ja&lt;/code&gt;, Kohei Watanabe), Norwegian (Bokmål, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;no&lt;/code&gt;, Tormod Bøe), Slovenian (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sl&lt;/code&gt;, Matjaž Jeran), Vietnamese (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;vi&lt;/code&gt;, Trần Thị Hoàng Hà).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Improvements in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nops_eval()&lt;/code&gt;: Show exam ID in HTML report and round points to four digits. The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;language=&lt;/code&gt; file paths do not have to be absolute anymore. For &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;interactive&lt;/code&gt; checking/fixing of registration IDs the width of scanned subimage is now adapted according to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;reglength&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;The actual writing of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nops_eval()&lt;/code&gt; results has been modularized (with contributions from Kenji Sato). Different &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nops_eval_write_&amp;lt;flavor&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; functions can be plugged in. At the moment there is only the default writer (optimized for OpenOLAT) but further flavors are planned (including a standalone workflow and one for Moodle).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Function &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nops_language()&lt;/code&gt; is now exported as part of the user interface (only internal previously). Based on a language specification in a DCF file this sets up a list with language texts (possibly converted to HTML).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;improvements-and-bug-fixes&quot;&gt;Improvements and bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;New exercise &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/capitals/&quot;&gt;capitals&lt;/a&gt; that illustrates how a certain number of true/false items can be chosen randomly from a longer list. The exercise can also be switched from &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mchoice&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;schoice&lt;/code&gt; without any further necessary modifications. Finally, the exercise illustrates that UTF-8 encoding is needed for the Rmd version while in the Rnw version the few special characters can be coded in ASCII using LaTeX commands.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;All LaTeX templates that use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\fontfamily{phv}&lt;/code&gt; now also gained a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\usepackage{helvet}&lt;/code&gt; to ensure that the corresponding LaTeX packages are installed. When using &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tinytex&lt;/code&gt; (see above) the corresponding LaTeX packages will be installed if not yet available upon first usage.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;In R/Markdown exercises the question/solution answerlist can now use not only &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; but also &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; as the symbol for bullet points (suggested by Ben Kasel).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2pdf()&lt;/code&gt; where the case of multiple duplicated supplement names was not handled correctly (reported by TwelveFifths on StackOverflow).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Improved &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;xexams()&lt;/code&gt; so that full file paths to exercise files also work on Windows.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;read_metainfo()&lt;/code&gt; now assures a non-&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;NULL&lt;/code&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exname&lt;/code&gt;. The default is to use “R/exams exercise”.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Fixed a bug in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;extract_items()&lt;/code&gt; which incorrectly dropped the last element in an answerlist if it was completely empty (even without a trailing space). This was a problem for cloze exercises with ##ANSWER## patterns, leading to a questionlist that was too short (reported by Julia Guggenberger).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Various fixes and improvements in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2qti21()&lt;/code&gt; (and thus inherited by &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2openolat()&lt;/code&gt;): Support of cloze and essay type exercises has been much improved, fixing bugs in the XML and meta-information handling. String exercises work again. The internally-generated XML labels are more robust now avoiding spaces and leading integers.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;The package depends on R &amp;gt;= 3.4.0 now, which enables plugging a custom svg device into &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Sweave()&lt;/code&gt;. In previous versions of the package a workaround was included that works for R &amp;lt; 3.4.0 (but required writing into the global environment which is avoided now).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</content>
			
				<category term="general" />
			
			
				<category term="R" />
			
				<category term="exams" />
			
				<category term="LaTeX" />
			
			<published>2020-04-09T00:00:00+02:00</published>
		</entry>
	
    
    
		<entry>
			<id>http://www.R-exams.org/templates/capitals/</id>
			<title>capitals: Knowledge Quiz Question about Capitals around the World</title>
			<link href="http://www.R-exams.org/templates/capitals/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="capitals: Knowledge Quiz Question about Capitals around the World" />
			<updated>2020-04-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Achim Zeileis</name>
					
					
						<email>Achim.Zeileis@R-project.org</email>
					
					
						<uri>https://eeecon.uibk.ac.at/~zeileis/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Exercise template for a multiple-choice knowledge quiz question with flexible shuffling of the alternatives.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.R-exams.org/templates/capitals/">&lt;p&gt;Exercise template for a multiple-choice knowledge quiz question with flexible shuffling of the alternatives.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t1 b1&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Name:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-8 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;capitals&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t1 b1&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Type:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-8 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tag/mchoice/&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mchoice&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t1 b1&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Related:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-8 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/swisscapital/&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;swisscapital&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t20 b1&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Description:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-8 columns&quot;&gt;Knowledge quiz question about capitals (vs. large cities) in countries around the world with 5 correct and 6 false alternatives which are shuffled randomly in each version of the exercise. Due to the large number of both correct and false alternatives, the same template could also easily be turned into a single-choice (schoice) exercise. The Rmd exercise is in UTF-8 encoding while the Rnw exercise avoids non-ASCII characters by using LaTeX commands.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t1 b1&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Solution feedback:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-8 columns&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t1 b1&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Randomization:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-8 columns&quot;&gt;Shuffling (5 out of 11 alternatives)&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t1 b1&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mathematical notation:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-8 columns&quot;&gt;No&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t1 b1&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Verbatim R input/output:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-8 columns&quot;&gt;No&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t1 b1&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Images:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-8 columns&quot;&gt;No&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t1 b1&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Other supplements:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-8 columns&quot;&gt;No&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t20 b1&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Template:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-08-capitals//capitals.Rnw&quot;&gt;capitals.Rnw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-08-capitals//capitals.Rmd&quot;&gt;capitals.Rmd&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t1 b1&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Raw:&lt;/b&gt; (1 random version)&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-08-capitals//capitals.tex&quot;&gt;capitals.tex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-08-capitals//capitals.md&quot;&gt;capitals.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t1 b1&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;PDF:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-08-capitals//capitals-Rnw.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-08-capitals//capitals-Rnw-pdf.png&quot; alt=&quot;capitals-Rnw-pdf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-08-capitals//capitals-Rmd.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-08-capitals//capitals-Rmd-pdf.png&quot; alt=&quot;capitals-Rmd-pdf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t1 b20&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;HTML:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-08-capitals//capitals-Rnw.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-08-capitals//capitals-Rnw-html.png&quot; alt=&quot;capitals-Rnw-html&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;medium-4 columns&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-08-capitals//capitals-Rmd.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-08-capitals//capitals-Rmd-html.png&quot; alt=&quot;capitals-Rmd-html&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Demo code:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;library(&amp;quot;exams&amp;quot;) set.seed(403) exams2html(&amp;quot;capitals.Rnw&amp;quot;) set.seed(403) exams2pdf(&amp;quot;capitals.Rnw&amp;quot;) set.seed(403) exams2html(&amp;quot;capitals.Rmd&amp;quot;) set.seed(403) exams2pdf(&amp;quot;capitals.Rmd&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
			
				<category term="templates" />
			
			
				<category term="mchoice" />
			
				<category term="multiple-choice" />
			
				<category term="knowledge" />
			
				<category term="quiz" />
			
				<category term="utf8" />
			
				<category term="switzerland" />
			
			<published>2020-04-08T00:00:00+02:00</published>
		</entry>
	
    
    
		<entry>
			<id>http://www.R-exams.org/general/whyr2020/</id>
			<title>Why R? Webinar on R/exams for E-Learning Quizzes and Beyond</title>
			<link href="http://www.R-exams.org/general/whyr2020/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why R? Webinar on R/exams for E-Learning Quizzes and Beyond" />
			<updated>2020-04-04T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Achim Zeileis</name>
					
					
						<email>Achim.Zeileis@R-project.org</email>
					
					
						<uri>https://eeecon.uibk.ac.at/~zeileis/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Webinar hosted by Why R? Foundation: Slides, video, and e-learning resources.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.R-exams.org/general/whyr2020/">&lt;p&gt;Webinar hosted by Why R? Foundation: Slides, video, and e-learning resources.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Why R? Webinar on R/exams for E-Learning Quizzes and Beyond&quot; src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/images/whyr2020.title.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;why-r-webinar-001&quot;&gt;Why R? Webinar 001&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/&quot;&gt;R/exams&lt;/a&gt; was presented in the first &lt;a href=&quot;http://whyr.pl/webinars/&quot;&gt;Why R? webinar&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://eeecon.uibk.ac.at/~zeileis/&quot;&gt;Achim Zeileis&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://r-addict.com/&quot;&gt;Marcin Kosiński&lt;/a&gt; was the host and did a great job setting up the Zoom session that was streamed live on YouTube where more than 100 participants joined the live chat.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Compared to previous presentations on R/exams, the webinar gave some emphasis to e-learning. Also, the presentation shared some experiences from Universität Innsbruck on how R/exams can assist the transition to distance learning due to the corona crisis in spring 2020.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This blog post provides various resources for those who did not attend the webinar or who want to explore the materials in some more detail. Most importantly the presentation slides are available in PDF format (under CC-BY):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-04-whyr2020/slides.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-04-whyr2020/slides.png&quot; alt=&quot;slides.pdf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;video&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thanks to the great job done by the Why R? organizers, the recording of the live stream is available on YouTube:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PnyCR7q4P4Q&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-04-whyr2020/youtube.png&quot; alt=&quot;YouTube&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;e-learning&quot;&gt;E-Learning&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;To illustrate the e-learning capabilities supported by R/exams, the presentation went through an online quiz generated by R/exams and imported into &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.OpenOLAT.com/&quot;&gt;OpenOLAT&lt;/a&gt;, an open-source learning management system (available under the Apache License). The online test is made available again here for anonymous guest access. &lt;em&gt;(Note however, that the system only has one guest user so that when you start the test there may already be some test results from a previous guest session. In that case you can finish the test and also start it again.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lms.uibk.ac.at/url/RepositoryEntry/2823520256/CourseNode/97603810083315?guest=true&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-04-04-whyr2020/openolat.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenOLAT&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A detailed description of the generation and import of this online quiz is available in the recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/elearning/&quot;&gt;R/exams e-learning tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting started&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;Further resources for getting started with R/exams are available in these tutorials:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/installation/&quot;&gt;Installing R/exams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/first_steps/&quot;&gt;First Steps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/stresstest/&quot;&gt;Stress Testing Dynamic R/exams Exercises&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</content>
			
				<category term="general" />
			
			
				<category term="R" />
			
				<category term="exams" />
			
				<category term="e-learning" />
			
			<published>2020-04-04T00:00:00+02:00</published>
		</entry>
	
    
    
		<entry>
			<id>http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/elearning/</id>
			<title>E-Learning Quizzes with R/exams for Moodle and OpenOLAT</title>
			<link href="http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/elearning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="E-Learning Quizzes with R/exams for Moodle and OpenOLAT" />
			<updated>2020-03-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Achim Zeileis</name>
					
					
						<email>Achim.Zeileis@R-project.org</email>
					
					
						<uri>https://eeecon.uibk.ac.at/~zeileis/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Step-by-step tutorials for generating, importing, and customizing online tests and quizzes using exams2moodle() and exams2openolat() in R/exams.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/elearning/">&lt;p&gt;Step-by-step tutorials for generating, importing, and customizing online tests and quizzes using exams2moodle() and exams2openolat() in R/exams.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;E-Learning Quizzes with R/exams for Moodle and OpenOLAT&quot; src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/images/elearning.title.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t20 b20&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;small-8 medium-9 columns&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;E-learning resources such as online tests and quizzes or more formal e-exams are very useful in a variety of settings: formative vs. summative assessments; in-class vs. distance learning; synchronous vs. asynchronous; small vs. large groups of students. Some typical examples are outlined here.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;small-4 medium-3 columns&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/images/elearning-goal.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Motivation&quot; /&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Short tests/quizzes conducted in-class (synchronously) as a quick assessment of content the students had to prepare before class. In a flipped classroom approach the test/quiz might also be conducted after a collaboration phase in class.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Asynchronous online tests that students can do in their own time (e.g., over several days) to obtain (incentivized) feedback regarding their learning progress. Such tests might follow any form of content delivery, be it classical lectures or video screencasts or some other approach.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Synchronous e-exams conducted in-class or remotely (e.g., coupled with a safe exam browser) as a summative assessment at the end of a course.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org&quot;&gt;R/exams&lt;/a&gt; can support these scenarios by creating a sufficiently large number of randomized versions of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/intro/dynamic/&quot;&gt;dynamic exercises&lt;/a&gt; that can subsequently be imported into a learning management system (LMS). The actual quiz/test/exam is then conducted in the LMS only, i.e., without the need to have R running in the background, because all exercises and corresponding solutions have been pre-computed and stored in the LMS. Popular LMS include the open-source systems &lt;a href=&quot;https://moodle.org/&quot;&gt;Moodle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instructure.com/canvas/&quot;&gt;Canvas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openolat.com/?lang=en&quot;&gt;OpenOLAT&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ilias.de/en/&quot;&gt;Ilias&lt;/a&gt; or the commerical &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blackboard.com/&quot;&gt;Blackboard&lt;/a&gt; system. R/exams provides suitable interfaces for all of these but the capabilities differ somewhat between the LMS. In the following we focus on Moodle and OpenOLAT, both of which provide very flexible and powerful assessment modules.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;creation-in-rexams&quot;&gt;Creation in R/exams&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t20 b20&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;small-8 medium-9 columns&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Just like for other R/exams interfaces the starting point is putting together a vector or list of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/intro/dynamic/&quot;&gt;(potentially) dynamic exercises&lt;/a&gt; in R. From these exercises - in either R/Markdown or R/LaTeX format - a number of random replications can be drawn using either &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2moodle()&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2openolat()&lt;/code&gt;, respectively. Both interfaces support all R/exams exercise types: single-choice (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;schoice&lt;/code&gt;), multiple-choice (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mchoice&lt;/code&gt;), numeric (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;num&lt;/code&gt;), string (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;string&lt;/code&gt;), or combinations of these (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cloze&lt;/code&gt;). See the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/first_steps/&quot;&gt;First Steps&lt;/a&gt; tutorial for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;small-4 medium-3 columns&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/images/elearning-create.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Creation&quot; /&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here, we use a collection of exercise templates that are all shipped within the R/exams package and that cover a broad range of different question types as well as different randomyly-generated content (shuffling, random parameters, R output, graphics, simulated data sets).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;table&gt; &lt;thead&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Exercise template&lt;/th&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Task&lt;/th&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/thead&gt; &lt;tbody&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/swisscapital/&quot;&gt;swisscapital&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;schoice&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Knowledge quiz question with basic shuffling&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/deriv/&quot;&gt;deriv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;num&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Computing the derivative of a function with randomized parameters&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/ttest/&quot;&gt;ttest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mchoice&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Interpretation of R output from &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;t.test()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/boxplots/&quot;&gt;boxplots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mchoice&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Interpretation of parallel boxplots&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/function/&quot;&gt;function&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;string&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Knowledge quiz question where the answer is the name of an R function&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/lm/&quot;&gt;lm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cloze&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Conducting a simple linear regression based on a randomly-generated CSV file&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/fourfold2/&quot;&gt;fourfold2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cloze&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Completing a fourfold table based on verbal description with randomized parameters&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/tbody&gt; &lt;/table&gt; &lt;p&gt;First, we load the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams&lt;/code&gt; package and define a vector with all exercise &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.Rmd&lt;/code&gt; file names.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;library(&amp;quot;exams&amp;quot;) elearn_exam &amp;lt;- c(&amp;quot;swisscapital.Rmd&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;deriv.Rmd&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;ttest.Rmd&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;boxplots.Rmd&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;function.Rmd&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;lm.Rmd&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;fourfold2.Rmd&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Alternatively, the corresponding &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.Rnw&lt;/code&gt; files could be used, yielding virtually identical output.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Second, we generate a Moodle XML file with 3 random replications of each of the exercises.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;set.seed(2020-03-15) exams2moodle(elearn_exam, n = 3, name = &amp;quot;R-exams&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;This yields the file &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-03-28-elearning//R-exams.xml&quot;&gt;R-exams.xml&lt;/a&gt; that can be imported into Moodle.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Analogously, a ZIP archive containing QTI 2.1 XML files (Question &amp;amp; Test Interoperability standard) for import into OpenOLAT.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;set.seed(2020-03-15) rxm &amp;lt;- exams2openolat(elearn_exam, n = 3, name = &amp;quot;R-exams&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;The resulting output file is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-03-28-elearning//R-exams.zip&quot;&gt;R-exams.zip&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Moreover, to show that the object returned within R can also be useful we have assigned the output of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2openolat()&lt;/code&gt; to an object &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rxm&lt;/code&gt;. This is not necessary but inspecting this object might be helpful when developing and testing new exercises. In particular, we can easily extract the meta-information regarding the correct answers in all randomly generated exercises.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;exams_metainfo(rxm)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## ## exam1 ## 1. Swiss Capital: 4 ## 2. derivative exp: 38.72 (38.71--38.73) ## 3. 2-sample t-test: 1, 2, 5 ## 4. Parallel boxplots: 2, 4, 5 ## 5. R functions: lm ## 6. Linear regression: FALSE, FALSE, TRUE | -0.861 ## 7. fourfold: 4.44 | 19.74 | 1.56 | 74.26 | 24.18 | 75.82 | 6 | 94 | 100 ## ## exam2 ## 1. Swiss Capital: 4 ## 2. derivative exp: 2 (1.99--2.01) ## 3. 2-sample t-test: 3 ## 4. Parallel boxplots: 2, 3, 4 ## 5. R functions: vcov ## 6. Linear regression: FALSE, TRUE, FALSE | 0.531 ## 7. fourfold: 5.76 | 23.92 | 2.24 | 68.08 | 29.68 | 70.32 | 8 | 92 | 100 ## ## exam3 ## 1. Swiss Capital: 2 ## 2. derivative exp: 2.05 (2.04--2.06) ## 3. 2-sample t-test: 2, 3 ## 4. Parallel boxplots: 2, 4, 5 ## 5. R functions: glm ## 6. Linear regression: TRUE, FALSE, FALSE | 0.024 ## 7. fourfold: 6.5 | 22.5 | 3.5 | 67.5 | 29 | 71 | 10 | 90 | 100 &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;import-into-moodle-and-openolat&quot;&gt;Import into Moodle and OpenOLAT&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;row t20 b20&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;small-8 medium-9 columns&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finally, the output files generated above can be imported into the Moodle and OpenOLAT learning management system, respectively. In Moodle the random exercises are imported into a question bank based on which a quiz with randomly-selected questions can be constructed. In OpenOLAT the import directly yields a test learning resource that can then be embedded in a course.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;small-4 medium-3 columns&quot;&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/images/elearning-import.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Import&quot; /&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;moodle-import&quot;&gt;Moodle import&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;A step-by-step video guide to importing and customizing the quiz in Moodle is available on YouTube at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5K9hrE3YkPs&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5K9hrE3YkPs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5K9hrE3YkPs&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-03-28-elearning/moodle.png&quot; alt=&quot;Moodle import&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;openolat-import&quot;&gt;OpenOLAT import&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;p&gt;A step-by-step video guide to importing and customizing the test in OpenOLAT is available on YouTube at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ZhdmoDtUSA&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ZhdmoDtUSA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ZhdmoDtUSA&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2020-03-28-elearning/openolat.png&quot; alt=&quot;OpenOLAT import&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
			
				<category term="tutorials" />
			
			
				<category term="exams2moodle" />
			
				<category term="exams2openolat" />
			
				<category term="e-learning" />
			
				<category term="quiz" />
			
				<category term="num" />
			
				<category term="mchoice" />
			
				<category term="schoice" />
			
				<category term="cloze" />
			
				<category term="R" />
			
			<published>2020-03-28T00:00:00+01:00</published>
		</entry>
	
    
    
		<entry>
			<id>http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/stresstest/</id>
			<title>Stress Testing Dynamic R/exams Exercises</title>
			<link href="http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/stresstest/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stress Testing Dynamic R/exams Exercises" />
			<updated>2019-07-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Achim Zeileis</name>
					
					
						<email>Achim.Zeileis@R-project.org</email>
					
					
						<uri>https://eeecon.uibk.ac.at/~zeileis/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Before actually using a dynamic exercise in a course it should be thoroughly tested. While certain aspects require critical reading by a human, other aspects can be automatically stress-tested in R.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/stresstest/">&lt;p&gt;Before actually using a dynamic exercise in a course it should be thoroughly tested. While certain aspects require critical reading by a human, other aspects can be automatically stress-tested in R.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Stress Testing Dynamic R/exams Exercises&quot; src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/images/stresstest.title.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;motivation&quot;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;After a dynamic exercise has been developed, thorough testing is recommended before administering the exercise in a student assessment. Therefore, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org&quot;&gt;R/exams&lt;/a&gt; package provides the function &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;stresstest_exercise()&lt;/code&gt; to aid teachers in this process. While the teachers still have to assess themselves how sensible/intelligible/appropriate/… the exercise is, the R function can help check:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;whether the data-generating process works without errors or infinite loops,&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;how long a random draw from the exercise takes,&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;what range the correct results fall into,&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;whether there are patterns in the results that students could leverage for guessing the correct answer.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;To do so, the function takes the exercise and compiles it hundreds or thousands of times. In each of the iterations the correct solution(s) and the run times are stored in a data frame along with all variables (numeric/integer/character of length 1) created by the exercise. This data frame can then be used to examine undesirable behavior of the exercise. More specifically, for some values of the variables the solutions might become extreme in some way (e.g., very small or very large etc.) or single-choice/multiple-choice answers might not be uniformly distributed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In our experience such patterns are not rare in practice and our students are very good at picking them up, leveraging them for solving the exercises in exams.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;example-calculating-binomial-probabilities&quot;&gt;Example: Calculating binomial probabilities&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;In order to exemplify the work flow, let’s consider a simple exercise about calculating a certain binomial probability:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;table&gt; &lt;tbody&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td&gt;According to a recent survey &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;100 - p&lt;/code&gt; percent of all customers in grocery stores pay cash while the rest use their credit or cash card. You are currently waiting in the queue at the checkout of a grocery story with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; customers in front of you. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt; What is the probability (in percent) that &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; or more of the other customers pay with their card?&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/tbody&gt; &lt;/table&gt; &lt;p&gt;In R, the correct answer for this exercise can be computed as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;100 * pbinom(k - 1, size = n, prob = p/100, lower.tail = FALSE)&lt;/code&gt; which we ask for in the exercise (rounded to two digits).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the folllowing, we illustrate typical problems of parameterizing such an exercise: For an exercise with numeric answer we only need to sample the variables &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;p&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;k&lt;/code&gt;. For a single-choice version we also need a certain number of wrong answers (or “distractors”), comprised of typical errors and/or random numbers. For both types of exercises we first show a version that exhibits some undesirable properties and then proceed to an improved version of it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;table&gt; &lt;thead&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;#&lt;/th&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Exercise templates&lt;/th&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/thead&gt; &lt;tbody&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/binomial1.Rmd&quot;&gt;binomial1.Rmd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/binomial1.Rnw&quot;&gt;binomial1.Rnw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;num&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;First attempt with poor parameter ranges.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/binomial2.Rmd&quot;&gt;binomial2.Rmd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/binomial2.Rnw&quot;&gt;binomial2.Rnw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;num&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;As in #1 but with some parameter ranges improved.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/binomial3.Rmd&quot;&gt;binomial3.Rmd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/binomial3.Rnw&quot;&gt;binomial3.Rnw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;schoice&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Single-choice version based on #2 but with too many typical wrong solutions and poor random answers.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/binomial4.Rmd&quot;&gt;binomial4.Rmd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/binomial4.Rnw&quot;&gt;binomial4.Rnw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;schoice&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;As in #3 but with improved sampling of both typical errors and random solutions.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/tbody&gt; &lt;/table&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you want to replicate the illustrations below you can easily download all four exercises from within R. Here, we show how to do so for the R/Markdown (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.Rmd&lt;/code&gt;) version of the exercise but equivalently you can also use the R\LaTeX version (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.Rnw&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;for(i in paste0(extra, 1:4, &amp;quot;.Rmd&amp;quot;)) download.file( paste0(&amp;quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/&amp;quot;, i), i)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;numerical-exercise-first-attempt&quot;&gt;Numerical exercise: First attempt&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;In a first attempt we generate the parameters in the exercise as:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;## success probability in percent (= pay with card) p &amp;lt;- sample(0:4, size = 1) ## number of attempts (= customers in queue) n &amp;lt;- sample(6:9, size = 1) ## minimum number of successes (= customers who pay with card) k &amp;lt;- sample(2:4, 1)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let’s stress test this exercise:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;s1 &amp;lt;- stresstest_exercise(&amp;quot;binomial1.Rmd&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## 1/2/3/4/5/6/7/8/9/10/11/12/13/14/15/16/17/18/19/20/21/22/23/24/25/26/27/28/29/30/31/32/33/34/35/36/37/38/39/40/41/42/43/44/45/46/47/48/49/50/51/52/53/54/55/56/57/58/59/60/61/62/63/64/65/66/67/68/69/70/71/72/73/74/75/76/77/78/79/80/81/82/83/84/85/86/87/88/89/90/91/92/93/94/95/96/97/98/99/100 &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;By default this generates 100 random draws from the exercise with seeds from 1 to 100. The seeds are also printed in the R console, seperated by slashes. Therefore, it is easy to reproduce errors that might occur when running the stress test, i.e., just &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;set.seed(i)&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;i&lt;/code&gt; being the problematic iteration and subsequently run something like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2html()&lt;/code&gt; or run the code for generating the parameters manually.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here, no errors occurred but further examination shows that parameters have clearly been too extreme:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;plot(s1)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/stresstest1-overview-1.svg&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk stresstest1-overview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The left panel shows the distribution run times which shows that this was fast without any problems. However, the distribution of solutions in the right panel shows that almost all solutions are extremely small. In fact, when accessing the solutions from the object &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;s1&lt;/code&gt; and summarizing them we see that a large proportion was exactly zero (due to rounding).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;summary(s1$solution)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## Min. 1st Qu. Median Mean 3rd Qu. Max. ## 0.0000 0.0000 0.0200 0.5239 0.3100 4.7800 &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;You might have already noticed the source of the problems when we presented the code above: the values for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;p&lt;/code&gt; are extremely small (and even include 0) but also &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; is rather large. But even if we didn’t notice this in the code directly we could have detected it visually by plotting the solution against the parameter variables from the exercise:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;plot(s1, type = &amp;quot;solution&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/stresstest1-solution-1.svg&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk stresstest1-solution&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remark:&lt;/em&gt; In addition to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;solution&lt;/code&gt; the object &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;s1&lt;/code&gt; contains the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;seeds&lt;/code&gt;, the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;runtime&lt;/code&gt;, and a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;data.frame&lt;/code&gt; with all &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;objects&lt;/code&gt; of length 1 that were newly created within the exercise. Sometimes it is useful to explore these in more detail manually.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;names(s1)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## [1] &amp;quot;seeds&amp;quot; &amp;quot;runtime&amp;quot; &amp;quot;objects&amp;quot; &amp;quot;solution&amp;quot; &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;names(s1$objects)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## [1] &amp;quot;k&amp;quot; &amp;quot;n&amp;quot; &amp;quot;p&amp;quot; &amp;quot;sol&amp;quot; &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;numerical-exercise-improved-version&quot;&gt;Numerical exercise: Improved version&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;To fix the problems detected above, we increase the range for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;p&lt;/code&gt; to be between 10 and 30 percent and reduce &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;k&lt;/code&gt; to values from 1 to 3, i.e., employ the following lines in the exercise:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;p &amp;lt;- sample(10:30, size = 1) k &amp;lt;- sample(1:3, 1)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Stress testing this modified exercise yields solutions with a much better spread:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;s2 &amp;lt;- stresstest_exercise(&amp;quot;binomial2.Rmd&amp;quot;) plot(s2)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/stresstest2-overview-1.svg&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk stresstest2-overview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Closer inspection shows that solutions can still become rather small:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;summary(s2$solution)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## Min. 1st Qu. Median Mean 3rd Qu. Max. ## 3.31 20.31 50.08 47.41 72.52 94.80 &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;For fine tuning we might be interested in finding out when the threshold of 5 percent probability is exceeded, depending on the variables &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;p&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;k&lt;/code&gt;. This can be done graphically via:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;plot(s2, type = &amp;quot;solution&amp;quot;, variables = c(&amp;quot;p&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;k&amp;quot;), threshold = 5)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/stresstest2-solution-1.svg&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk stresstest2-solution&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So maybe we could increase the minimum for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;p&lt;/code&gt; from 10 to 15 percent. In the following single-choice version of the exercise we will do so in order leave more room for incorrect answers below the correct solution.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;single-choice-exercise-first-attempt&quot;&gt;Single-choice exercise: First attempt&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Building on the numeric example above we now move on to set up a corresponding single-choice exercise. This is supported by more learning management systems, e.g., for live voting or for written exams that are scanned automatically. Thus, in addition to the correct solution we simply need to set up a certain number of distractors. Our idea is to use two distractors that are based on typical errors students may make plus two random distractors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;ok &amp;lt;- FALSE while(!ok) { ## two typical errors: 1-p vs. p, pbinom vs. dbinom err1 &amp;lt;- 100 * pbinom(k - 1, size = n, prob = 1 - p/100, lower.tail = FALSE) err2 &amp;lt;- 100 * dbinom(k, size = n, prob = p/100) ## two random errors rand &amp;lt;- runif(2, min = 0, max = 100) ## make sure solutions and errors are unique ans &amp;lt;- round(c(sol, err1, err2, rand), digits = 2) ok &amp;lt;- length(unique(ans)) == 5 }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Additionally, the code makes sure that we really do obtain five distinct numbers. Even if the probability of two distractors coinciding is very small, it might occur eventually. Finally, because the correct solution is always the first element in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ans&lt;/code&gt; we can set &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exsolution&lt;/code&gt; in the meta-information to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;10000&lt;/code&gt; but then have to set &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exshuffle&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TRUE&lt;/code&gt; so that the answers are shuffled in each random draw.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So we are quite hopeful that our exercise will do ok in the stress test:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;s3 &amp;lt;- stresstest_exercise(&amp;quot;binomial3.Rmd&amp;quot;) plot(s3)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/stresstest3-overview-1.svg&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk stresstest3-overview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The runtimes are still ok (indicating that the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;while&lt;/code&gt; loop was rarely used) as are the numeric solutions - and due to shuffling the position of the correct solution in the answer list is completely random. However, the &lt;em&gt;rank&lt;/em&gt; of the solution is not: the correct solution is never the smallest or the largest of the answer options. The reasons for this surely have to be our typical errors:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;plot(s3, type = &amp;quot;solution&amp;quot;, variables = c(&amp;quot;err1&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;err2&amp;quot;))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/stresstest3-solution-1.svg&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk stresstest3-solution&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And indeed &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;err1&lt;/code&gt; is always (much) larger than the correct solution and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;err2&lt;/code&gt; is always smaller. Of course, we could have realized this from the way we set up those typical errors but we didn’t have to - due to the stress test. Also, whether or not we consider this to be problem is a different matter. Possibly, if a certain error is very common it does not matter whether it is always larger or smaller than the correct solution.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;single-choice-exercise-improved-version&quot;&gt;Single-choice exercise: Improved version&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here, we continue to improve the exercise by randomly selecting only one of the two typical errors. Then, sometimes the error is smaller and sometimes larger than the correct solution.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;err &amp;lt;- sample(c(err1, err2), 1)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Moreover, we leverage the function &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;num_to_schoice()&lt;/code&gt; (or equivalently &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;num2schoice()&lt;/code&gt;) to sample the random distractors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;sc &amp;lt;- num_to_schoice(sol, wrong = err, range = c(2, 98), delta = 0.1)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Again, this is run in a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;while()&lt;/code&gt; loop to make sure that potential errors are caught (where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;num_to_schoice()&lt;/code&gt; returns &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;NULL&lt;/code&gt; and issues a warning). This has a couple of desirable features:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;num_to_schoice()&lt;/code&gt; first samples how many random solutions should be to the left and to the right of the correct solution. This makes sure that even if the correct solution is not in the middle of the admissible range (in our case: either close to 0 or to 100), it is not more likely to get greater vs. smaller distractors.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;We can set a minimum distance &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;delta&lt;/code&gt; between all answer options (correct solution and distractors) to make sure that answers are not too close.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Shuffling is also carried out automatically so &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exshuffle&lt;/code&gt; does not have to be set.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finally, the list of possible answers automatically gets LaTeX math markup &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$...$&lt;/code&gt; for nicer formatting in certain situations. Therefore, for consistency, the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;binomial4&lt;/code&gt; version of the exercise uses math markup for all numbers in the question.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The corresponding stress test looks sataisfactory now:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint &quot;&gt;s4 &amp;lt;- stresstest_exercise(&amp;quot;binomial4.Rmd&amp;quot;) plot(s4)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-10-stresstest/stresstest4-overview-1.svg&quot; alt=&quot;plot of chunk stresstest4-overview&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Of course, there is still at least one number that is either larger or smaller than the correct solution so that the correct solution takes rank 1 or 5 less often than ranks 2 to 4. But this seems to be a reasonable compromise.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;When drawing many random versions from a certain exercise template, it is essential to thoroughly check that exercise before using it in real exams. Most importantly, of course, the authors should make sure that the story and setup is sensible, question and solution are carefully formulated, etc. But then the technical aspects should be checked as well. This should include checking whether the exercise can be rendered correctly into PDF via &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2pdf(...)&lt;/code&gt; and into HTML via &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2html(...)&lt;/code&gt; and/or possibly &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2html(..., converter = &quot;pandoc-mathjax&quot;)&lt;/code&gt; (to check different forms of math rendering). And when all of this has been checked, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;stresstest_exercise()&lt;/code&gt; can help to find further problems and/or patterns that can be detected when making many random draws.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The problems in this tutorial could be detected with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n = 100&lt;/code&gt; random draws. But it is possible that some edge cases occur only very rarely so that, dependending on the complexity of the data-generating process, it is often useful to use much higher values of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Note that in our &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;binomial*&lt;/code&gt; exercises it would also have been possible to set up all factorial combinations of input parameters, e.g., by &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;expand.grid(p = 15:30, n = 6:9, k = 1:3)&lt;/code&gt;. Then we could have asssessed directly which of these lead to ok solutions and which are too extreme. However, when the data-generating process becomes more complex this might not be so easy. The random exploration as done by &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;num_to_schoice()&lt;/code&gt; is still straightforward, though.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
			
				<category term="tutorials" />
			
			
				<category term="Rmd" />
			
				<category term="Rnw" />
			
				<category term="arithmetic" />
			
				<category term="numeric" />
			
				<category term="single-choice" />
			
				<category term="evaluation" />
			
				<category term="exams" />
			
			<published>2019-07-10T00:00:00+02:00</published>
		</entry>
	
    
    
		<entry>
			<id>http://www.R-exams.org/general/user2019/</id>
			<title>R/exams @ useR! 2019</title>
			<link href="http://www.R-exams.org/general/user2019/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="R/exams @ useR! 2019" />
			<updated>2019-07-09T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Achim Zeileis</name>
					
					
						<email>Achim.Zeileis@R-project.org</email>
					
					
						<uri>https://eeecon.uibk.ac.at/~zeileis/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>Pre-conference tutorial about R/exams at useR! 2019 (The R User Conference) in Toulouse: Slides, example code, and links to further information.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.R-exams.org/general/user2019/">&lt;p&gt;Pre-conference tutorial about R/exams at useR! 2019 (The R User Conference) in Toulouse: Slides, example code, and links to further information.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;R/exams @ useR! 2019&quot; src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/images/user2019.title.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;tutorial-at-user-2019&quot;&gt;Tutorial at useR! 2019&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Today, the pre-conference tutorials kick off this year’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://useR2019.R-project.org/&quot;&gt;useR! 2019&lt;/a&gt; conference. The organizers kindly invited &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/&quot;&gt;R/exams&lt;/a&gt; for one of these tutorials. This blog post provides some accompanying resources which may be of interest to those who do not attend the conference/tutorial. The plan is to roughly follow the outline below.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;table&gt; &lt;thead&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Content&lt;/th&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/thead&gt; &lt;tbody&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;14:00 &lt;br /&gt; 14:30 &lt;br /&gt; 15:00&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Introduction (overview, installation, written exam) &lt;br /&gt; Dynamic exercises (numeric, single choice, multiple choice, cloze) &lt;br /&gt; One-for-all (plain PDF, plain HTML, Moodle XML)&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;15:30&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;— &lt;em&gt;Break&lt;/em&gt; —&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;16:00 &lt;br /&gt; 16:30 &lt;br /&gt; 17:00&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;E-Learning (Moodle, Canvas, ARSnova, …) &lt;br /&gt; Written exams (NOPS) &lt;br /&gt; Outlook&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/tbody&gt; &lt;/table&gt; &lt;p&gt;Most importantly the presentation &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/slides.pdf&quot;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt; are available in PDF format (under CC-BY) along with an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/tutorial.R&quot;&gt;R script&lt;/a&gt; (under GPL-2 or GPL-3) for the examples:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/slides.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/slides.png&quot; alt=&quot;slides.pdf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/tutorial.R&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/tutorial.png&quot; alt=&quot;tutorial.R&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Below, the examples, code, and links from the slides and R script are also provided which might be more convenient for some readers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;To set up your computer for this tutorial, follow Steps 1-4 in the tutorial &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/installation/&quot;&gt;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/installation/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Subsequently, we start out with setps described in more detail in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/first_steps/&quot;&gt;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/first_steps/&lt;/a&gt;. The package is loaded and first we create an “exams skeleton” with:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;demo-*.R&lt;/code&gt; scripts&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exercises/&lt;/code&gt; folder with all &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.Rmd&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.Rnw&lt;/code&gt; exercises&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;templates/&lt;/code&gt; folder with various customizable templates&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nops/&lt;/code&gt; folder (empty) for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2nops()&lt;/code&gt; output&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;library(&quot;exams&quot;) exams_skeleton() &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;To check whether everything works we render a single-choice question (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/swisscapital/&quot;&gt;swisscapital&lt;/a&gt;, knowledge quiz about the Swiss capital) into a plain HTML and PDF format, respectively.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;exams2html(&quot;swisscapital.Rmd&quot;) exams2pdf(&quot;swisscapital.Rmd&quot;) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;And then we do the same for a numeric question with mathematical notation: (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/deriv/&quot;&gt;deriv&lt;/a&gt;, product rule for derivatives). By default &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2html()&lt;/code&gt; uses MathML for the mathematical notation and expects the browser to render it which works ok in Firefox and Safari. But for Chrome it is better to use MathJax, see this post about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/math/&quot;&gt;mathematical notation in web exams&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;exams2html(&quot;deriv.Rmd&quot;) exams2html(&quot;deriv.Rmd&quot;, converter = &quot;pandoc-mathjax&quot;) exams2pdf(&quot;deriv.Rmd&quot;) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finally, a useful trick for checking whether the meta-information associated with an exercise is processed correctly:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;exams_metainfo(exams2html(c(&quot;swisscapital.Rmd&quot;, &quot;deriv.Rmd&quot;))) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;dynamic-exercises&quot;&gt;Dynamic exercises&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;This section gives a tour of the dynamic exercises shipped along with the package. See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/intro/dynamic/&quot;&gt;http://www.R-exams.org/intro/dynamic/&lt;/a&gt; for the supported exercise types and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/&quot;&gt;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/&lt;/a&gt; for a list of all example exercises.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Additionally, there is a simple knowledge quiz question about useR! conferences: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/conferences.Rmd&quot;&gt;conferences.Rmd&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/conferences.Rnw&quot;&gt;conferences.Rnw&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And the following exercises are used to illustrate how to go from a static to a dynamic numeric or single-choice question, see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/static_num_schoice/&quot;&gt;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/static_num_schoice/&lt;/a&gt; for more details. While the tutorial uses a basic economic example about computing elasticities, the exercises below are basic arithmetic exercises about derivatives.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;table&gt; &lt;thead&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;#&lt;/th&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Exercise templates&lt;/th&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Dynamic?&lt;/th&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt; &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/thead&gt; &lt;tbody&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/expderiv1.Rmd&quot;&gt;expderiv1.Rmd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/expderiv1.Rnw&quot;&gt;expderiv1.Rnw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;num&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Fixed parameters and numeric solution.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/expderiv2.Rmd&quot;&gt;expderiv2.Rmd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/expderiv2.Rnw&quot;&gt;expderiv2.Rnw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;No&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;schoice&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;As in #1 but with single-choice solution (five answer alternatives).&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/expderiv3.Rmd&quot;&gt;expderiv3.Rmd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/expderiv3.Rnw&quot;&gt;expderiv3.Rnw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;num&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Randomly drawn parameters with dynamic computation of correct solution, based on #1.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/expderiv4.Rmd&quot;&gt;expderiv4.Rmd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/expderiv4.Rnw&quot;&gt;expderiv4.Rnw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;schoice&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Randomly drawn parameters (as in #3) with dynamically-generated single-choice solution (as in #2), computed by &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;num_to_schoice()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/expderiv5.Rmd&quot;&gt;expderiv5.Rmd&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/expderiv5.Rnw&quot;&gt;expderiv5.Rnw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;schoice&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;As in #4 but with the last alternative: &lt;em&gt;None of the above.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/tbody&gt; &lt;/table&gt; &lt;p&gt;All of these extra exercise files can be downloaded from within R and stored in the skeleton set up above:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;extra &amp;lt;- c(&quot;conferences&quot;, paste0(&quot;expderiv&quot;, 1:5)) extra &amp;lt;- c(paste0(extra, &quot;.Rnw&quot;), paste0(extra, &quot;.Rmd&quot;)) for(i in extra) download.file(paste0(&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2019-07-09-user2019/&quot;, i), i) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;To take a tour of the available exercise files, we switch to the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exercises/&lt;/code&gt; folder:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;setwd(&quot;exercises&quot;) dir() &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;numeric-exercises&quot;&gt;Numeric exercises&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;exams2html(c( &quot;deriv.Rmd&quot;, ## product rule for derivatives &quot;tstat.Rmd&quot;, ## 1-sample t-test statistic &quot;dist.Rmd&quot;, ## distances and the Pythagorean theorem &quot;regression.Rmd&quot;, ## simple linear regression (by hand) &quot;fruit.Rmd&quot;, ## image-based systems of linear equations (numeric) &quot;lagrange.Rmd&quot;, ## method of Lagrange multipliers &quot;currency8.Rmd&quot; ## convert currencies (UTF-8 encoding) )) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;single-choice-exercises&quot;&gt;Single-choice exercises&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;exams2html(c( &quot;swisscapital.Rmd&quot;, ## knowledge quiz question about the Swiss capital &quot;Rlogo.Rmd&quot;, ## knowledge quiz question about the R logo &quot;deriv2.Rmd&quot;, ## product rule for derivatives (single-choice, via num_to_schoice) &quot;tstat2.Rmd&quot;, ## 1-sample t-test statistic (single-choice, by hand) &quot;dist3.Rmd&quot;, ## distances and the Pythagorean theorem (single-choice, via num_to_schoice) &quot;fruit2.Rmd&quot;, ## image-based systems of linear equations (single-choice, via num_to_schoice) &quot;hessian.Rmd&quot;, ## 2x2 Hessian matrix (single-choice) &quot;logic.Rmd&quot; ## interpretation of logic gates (using TikZ) )) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;multiple-choice-exercises&quot;&gt;Multiple-choice exercises&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;exams2html(c( &quot;switzerland.Rmd&quot;, ## knowledge quiz question about Switzerland &quot;gaussmarkov.Rmd&quot;, ## knowledge quiz question about Gauss-Markov assumptions &quot;anova.Rmd&quot;, ## 1-way analysis of variance &quot;boxplots.Rmd&quot;, ## interpretation of 2-sample boxplots &quot;scatterplot.Rmd&quot;, ## interpretation of a scatterplot &quot;ttest.Rmd&quot;, ## interpretation of 2-sample t test &quot;relfreq.Rmd&quot;, ## interpretation of relative frequency tables &quot;cholesky.Rmd&quot;, ## Cholesky decomposition &quot;automaton.Rmd&quot; ## interpretation of automaton diagrams (using TikZ) )) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;string-exercises&quot;&gt;String exercises&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;exams2html(c( &quot;function.Rmd&quot;, ## string question about R functions &quot;countrycodes.Rmd&quot; ## string question about ISO country codes )) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;cloze-exercises&quot;&gt;Cloze exercises&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;These combine several num/schoice/mchoice/string parts:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;exams2html(c( &quot;lm.Rmd&quot;, ## simple linear regression (with CSV data, schoice/num) &quot;boxhist.Rmd&quot;, ## univariate exploration of a CSV file (schoice/num) &quot;confint2.Rmd&quot;, ## 2-sided confidence interval (num) &quot;dist2.Rmd&quot;, ## three distances in a Cartesian coordinate system (num) &quot;fourfold.Rmd&quot; ## fourfold table (num) )) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h4 id=&quot;stress-testing-dynamic-exercises&quot;&gt;Stress testing dynamic exercises&lt;/h4&gt; &lt;p&gt;The function &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;stresstest_exercise()&lt;/code&gt; can help to do some basic quality control of dynamic exercise templates. It runs the exercises &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; times (default: 100) with seeds &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;n&lt;/code&gt; and stores run time, solution, and accompanying variables (of length 1). This can help to spot problems or patterns in the exercises.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A simple example for a numeric exercise is:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;s3 &amp;lt;- stresstest_exercise(&quot;expderiv3.Rmd&quot;) plot(s3) plot(s3, type = &quot;solution&quot;) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;And for a single-choice exercise:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;s4 &amp;lt;- stresstest_exercise(&quot;expderiv4.Rmd&quot;) plot(s4) plot(s4, type = &quot;solution&quot;) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;To focus on typical errors the plots against the variables &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;err1&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;err2&lt;/code&gt; can either be created by the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;plot()&lt;/code&gt; method or “by hand” with some customization:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;plot(s4, type = &quot;solution&quot;, variables = c(&quot;err1&quot;, &quot;err2&quot;)) plot(res ~ err1, data = s4$objects) abline(0, 1) plot(res ~ err2, data = s4$objects) abline(0, 1) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finally, we switch back to the original folder:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;setwd(&quot;..&quot;) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;one-for-all&quot;&gt;One-for-all&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;A basic design idea for R/exams is that the same exercise can, in principle, be rendered into a wide range of different output formats. For standalone files the most important formats are PDF, HTML, and possibly also Docx:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;demo_exam &amp;lt;- c(&quot;swisscapital.Rmd&quot;, &quot;deriv.Rmd&quot;) exams2html(demo_exam, edir = &quot;exercises&quot;) exams2pdf(demo_exam, edir = &quot;exercises&quot;) exams2pandoc(demo_exam, edir = &quot;exercises&quot;) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;The layout can be customized using suitable templates, e.g.,&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;exams2pdf(demo_exam, edir = &quot;exercises&quot;, template = &quot;templates/exam.tex&quot;) exams2pdf(demo_exam, edir = &quot;exercises&quot;, template = &quot;templates/solution.tex&quot;) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2nops()&lt;/code&gt; internally sets up a template on the fly and then calls &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2pdf()&lt;/code&gt;. And e-learning exams (Moodle XML, QTI 1.2/2.1, …) are illustrated in the next section.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;e-learning-moodle-canvas-arsnova-&quot;&gt;E-Learning (Moodle, Canvas, ARSnova, …)&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Output for various e-learning formats can be generated in pretty much the same way as the standalone files above. The main difference is that not one file per exam is generated but a combined output file comprising the desired number of exam replications. For example for Moodle:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;elearn_exam &amp;lt;- c(&quot;conferences.Rmd&quot;, &quot;deriv.Rmd&quot;, &quot;ttest.Rmd&quot;, &quot;boxplots.Rmd&quot;, &quot;function.Rnw&quot;, &quot;lm.Rmd&quot;, &quot;fourfold2.Rmd&quot;, &quot;confint3.Rmd&quot;) set.seed(2019-07-09) exams2moodle(elearn_exam, n = 30, name = &quot;useR-2019&quot;, dir = &quot;output&quot;, edir = &quot;exercises&quot;) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;For the registered participants of the course the resulting online quiz is made available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://eeecon.uibk.ac.at/~moodle/&quot;&gt;https://eeecon.uibk.ac.at/~moodle/&lt;/a&gt;. You can login with your e-mail address and the numeric code sent to you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Analogously, the numeric and single-/multiple-choice questions (but not yet cloze) can be prepared for Canvas by:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;set.seed(2019-07-09) exams2canvas(elearn_exam[1:5], n = 3, name = &quot;useR-2019&quot;, dir = &quot;output&quot;, edir = &quot;exercises&quot;, duration = 15) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;For OpenOLAT all exercises except one Moodle-specific exercise can be used as well:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;set.seed(2019-07-09) exams2openolat(elearn_exam[1:7], n = 3, name = &quot;useR-2019-olat&quot;, dir = &quot;output&quot;, edir = &quot;exercises&quot;) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;For ARSnova only single- and multiple-choice questions have good support:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;choice_exam &amp;lt;- list( &quot;conferences.Rmd&quot;, &quot;deriv2.Rmd&quot;, c(&quot;ttest.Rmd&quot;, &quot;boxplots.Rmd&quot;) ) set.seed(2019-07-09) exams2arsnova(unlist(choice_exam), n = 1, name = &quot;useR-2019&quot;, dir = &quot;output&quot;, edir = &quot;exercises&quot;) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;written-exams-nops&quot;&gt;Written exams (NOPS)&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;The written demo exam from the tutorial can be replicated by:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{r}&quot;&gt;set.seed(2019-07-09) exams2nops(choice_exam, n = 35, name = &quot;useR-2019&quot;, dir = &quot;nops&quot;, edir = &quot;exercises&quot;, reglength = 8, blank = 1, date = &quot;2019-07-09&quot;, title = &quot;Demo Exam&quot;, institution = &quot;useR! 2019&quot;) &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;More details about creating and evaluating NOPS exams is provided in the tutorial at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/exams2nops/&quot;&gt;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/exams2nops/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
			
				<category term="general" />
			
			
				<category term="R" />
			
				<category term="Rmd" />
			
				<category term="Rnw" />
			
				<category term="exams" />
			
				<category term="e-learning" />
			
				<category term="moodle" />
			
				<category term="canvas" />
			
				<category term="written" />
			
				<category term="arithmetic" />
			
				<category term="num" />
			
				<category term="numeric" />
			
				<category term="schoice" />
			
				<category term="single-choice" />
			
				<category term="mchoice" />
			
				<category term="multiple-choice" />
			
				<category term="string" />
			
				<category term="cloze" />
			
				<category term="exams2arsnova" />
			
				<category term="exams2nops" />
			
				<category term="exams2moodle" />
			
			<published>2019-07-09T00:00:00+02:00</published>
		</entry>
	
    
    
		<entry>
			<id>http://www.R-exams.org/general/cran_release_234/</id>
			<title>CRAN Release of R/exams 2.3-3 and 2.3-4</title>
			<link href="http://www.R-exams.org/general/cran_release_234/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CRAN Release of R/exams 2.3-3 and 2.3-4" />
			<updated>2019-07-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
			
				
				<author>
					
						<name>Achim Zeileis</name>
					
					
						<email>Achim.Zeileis@R-project.org</email>
					
					
						<uri>https://eeecon.uibk.ac.at/~zeileis/</uri>
					
				</author>
			
			<summary>New minor releases of the R/exams package to CRAN, containing a new dedicated function for online quizzes/exams in the Canvas learning management system. Moreover, the update provides a range of smaller improvements and bug fixes.</summary>
			<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.R-exams.org/general/cran_release_234/">&lt;p&gt;New minor releases of the R/exams package to CRAN, containing a new dedicated function for online quizzes/exams in the Canvas learning management system. Moreover, the update provides a range of smaller improvements and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;CRAN Release of R/exams 2.3-3 and 2.3-4&quot; src=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/images/cran234.title.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Version 2.3-3 and subsequently 2.3-4 of the one-for-all exams generator &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/&quot;&gt;R/exams&lt;/a&gt; have been published on the Comprehensive R Archive Network at &lt;a href=&quot;https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=exams&quot;&gt;https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=exams&lt;/a&gt;. In the next days this will propagate to other CRAN mirrors along with Windows and OS X binary packages. Version 2.3-4 was necessary in addition to 2.3-3 to avoid CRAN check problems on platforms where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pandoc&lt;/code&gt; is not available (currently, OS X and Solaris). The development version of the package is now version 2.3-5 on R-Forge at &lt;a href=&quot;http://R-Forge.R-project.org/forum/?group_id=1337&quot;&gt;http://R-Forge.R-project.org/forum/?group_id=1337&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;canvas-support&quot;&gt;Canvas support&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;A new interface &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2canvas()&lt;/code&gt; for the open-source &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instructure.com/canvas/&quot;&gt;Canvas learning management system&lt;/a&gt; has been added. This is the first dedicated Canvas interface after previously some indirect support was available through either &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2blackboard()&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2qti12()&lt;/code&gt;. However, both of these had certain limitations for Canvas that the new function aims to overcome. The function has only received limited testing so far and is likely to improve in future version. Please report any problems to the package maintainer.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Essentially, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2canvas()&lt;/code&gt; is a wrapper function to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2qti12()&lt;/code&gt; along with a few Canvas-specific modifications of the QTI XML specification. Supported exercise types are: single-choice, multiple-choice, numeric, and string (but not yet cloze). Embedding mathematical notation, graphics, and data supplements also works.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;mathematical-notation-in-moodle&quot;&gt;Mathematical notation in Moodle&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;The default &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;converter&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2moodle()&lt;/code&gt; has been changed to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;pandoc-mathjax&quot;&lt;/code&gt;. Thus, instead of relying on the browser to render &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/math/&quot;&gt;mathematical notation&lt;/a&gt; from MathML, the MathJax plugin is now assumed to be enabled on the Moodle server (which is the default when setting up a new Moodle server). To employ MathML as in previous versions one can use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;converter = NULL&lt;/code&gt;. This either selects &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;pandoc-mathml&quot;&lt;/code&gt; (or equivalently &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;pandoc&quot;&lt;/code&gt;) or &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&quot;ttm&quot;&lt;/code&gt; depending on the markup used in the exercises.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;written-exams-nops&quot;&gt;Written exams (NOPS)&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Assure in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nops_scan()&lt;/code&gt; that scanned image file names contain no spaces.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\usepackage[...]{babel}&lt;/code&gt; support to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/nops_language/&quot;&gt;language specification&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2nops()&lt;/code&gt;. In addition to a new &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Babel: ...&lt;/code&gt; field, the language &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.dcf&lt;/code&gt; can also provide a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Header: ...&lt;/code&gt; field, e.g., for changing the font encoding or adding further options.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;In &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nops_eval()&lt;/code&gt; duplicated sheets (original + replacement) were sometimes omitted even if the student ID was just 000000 (i.e., not read correctly by &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nops_scan()&lt;/code&gt;). A check has been added that avoids this.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;improvements-and-bug-fixes&quot;&gt;Improvements and bug fixes&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams_skeleton()&lt;/code&gt; has been updated. The new default is &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;markup = &quot;markdown&quot;&lt;/code&gt; as this appears to be the more common choice for newcomers to R/exams. Furthermore, the list of exercises in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;demo-*.R&lt;/code&gt; scripts has been updated to use newer exercises as well (along with links to the web page: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/&quot;&gt;http://www.R-exams.org/templates/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Fixed bugs in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2qti21()&lt;/code&gt; (and hence &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2openolat()&lt;/code&gt;) for certain combinations of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;maxchars&lt;/code&gt; specifications in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;string&lt;/code&gt; exercises.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;For convenience, when &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2html(..., converter = &quot;pandoc-mathjax&quot;)&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;mathjax = TRUE&lt;/code&gt; is added automatically (unless explicitly switched off).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;print()&lt;/code&gt; method for &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams_metainfo&lt;/code&gt; objects received a new &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;block&lt;/code&gt; argument so that &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;print(exams_metainfo(x), which = 1, block = 5)&lt;/code&gt; prints the metainformation (type/solution) of the first exam in the object &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;x&lt;/code&gt; (output from any &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2xyz()&lt;/code&gt; function) in blocks of 5 exercises. Implemented for the blog about R/exams at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.R-exams.org/general/tamiu_finance&quot;&gt;Texas A&amp;amp;M International University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;For &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2openolat()&lt;/code&gt; the handling of the internal pandoc fixups was extended to replace &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;align=&quot;right&quot;&lt;/code&gt; in tables with &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;&lt;/code&gt; (and analogously for “left” and “center”).&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Changed the default of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fix_choice&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2arsnova()&lt;/code&gt;. Current versions of the official &lt;a href=&quot;https://arsnova.eu/&quot;&gt;ARSnova server&lt;/a&gt; have the LaTeX rendering in the choice options switched off. Hence, by setting &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fix_choice = TRUE&lt;/code&gt; by default the LaTeX math markup is removed.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Add &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\setkeys{Gin}{keepaspectratio}&lt;/code&gt; in the default &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2pdf()&lt;/code&gt; template for pandoc (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;plain8.tex&lt;/code&gt;) and in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2nops()&lt;/code&gt;. This is necessitated by a change in pandoc that now always sets &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;height=\textheight&lt;/code&gt; when &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;width=&lt;/code&gt; is specified, see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pandoc.org/faqs.html&quot;&gt;pandoc FAQ&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Added an &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;envir&lt;/code&gt; argument in &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;exams2moodle()&lt;/code&gt; that is passed on to &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;xweave()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;</content>
			
				<category term="general" />
			
			
				<category term="R" />
			
				<category term="exams" />
			
				<category term="canvas" />
			
			<published>2019-07-08T00:00:00+02:00</published>
		</entry>
	
</feed>
