<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/xslt/rss.xslt" ?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/assets/css/rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>R/exams</title>
		<description>Automatic generation  and evaluation of exams. From Markdown, LaTeX and R code to standalone documents, learning management systems and live voting.</description>
		<link>http://www.R-exams.org/</link>
		<atom:link href="http://www.R-exams.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
    
    
			<item>
        <title><![CDATA[ R/exams for Blended Learning in a Mathematics 101 Course]]></title>
				<link>http://www.R-exams.org/general/uibk_math/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        
        <description><![CDATA[
    
    <p>Overview of how R/exams is used to assist learning, feedback, and assessment in a large introductory mathematics course at Universität Innsbruck.</p>
    
    
    <p><img alt=" R/exams for Blended Learning in a Mathematics 101 Course" src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/uibkmath.title.png" /></p>
    
    <h3 id="motivation">Motivation</h3>

<p>Many statisticians regularly teach large lecture courses on statistics,
probability, or mathematics for students from other fields such as business and
economics, social sciences and psychology, etc. A common challenge in such
courses is that many variations of similar exercises are needed for written
exams, online tests conducted in learning management systems (LMS, such as Moodle,
Blackboard, etc.), or live quizzes with voting via smartphones or tablets.</p>

<p>Here, it is shown how the <a href="https://www.uibk.ac.at/statistics/">Department of Statistics</a>
at <a href="https://www.uibk.ac.at/">Universität Innsbruck</a> manages the first-year
mathematics 101 course for economics and business students, attended by
about 500 to 1,000 students per semester. The course is accessible through the
university’s LMS (an <a href="https://www.openolat.com/">OpenOLAT</a>
system), including anonymous <em>“Guest access”</em> for most materials. So you can either
look at the screen shots presented below in this blog post or try out the course yourself:
<a href="https://lms.uibk.ac.at/url/RepositoryEntry/3051978752?guest=true">https://lms.uibk.ac.at/url/RepositoryEntry/3051978752?guest=true</a>.
(Notes: The course materials are in German but also non-German-speakers should get a
good impression of how things are tied together. The online tests contain mathematical
equations in MathML which is displayed by browsers with MathML support like Firefox or
Safari - <em>but not Chrome</em>.)</p>

<h3 id="course-overview">Course overview</h3>

<p>As highschool knowledge about mathematics is rather heterogeneous among the students, the
course has been designed so that they can learn either synchronously (in a classical
lecture that is also streamed live) or asynchronously (with a textbook and/or screencasts).
This way students can decide which parts of the content just need reviewing and which
need deepening. Similarly, they can get feedback (not directly relevant for their grade) during
lecture and tutorial sessions synchronously or asynchronously “in their own time”. Finally,
the assessment is also done in two parts: online tests that they can do over the course of the semester
(at any time within a 3.5-day window each) and a classical written exam at the end of the semester.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: left"> </th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Learning</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Feedback</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Assessment</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left"><strong>Synchronous</strong></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Lecture <br /> Live stream</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="#live-quiz">Live quiz</a> <br /> (+ Tutorial)</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="#written-exam">Written exam</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left"><strong>Asynchronous</strong></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Textbook <br /> Screencast</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="#online-test">Self test</a> <br /> (+ Forum)</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="#online-test">Online test</a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Subsequently, it will be discussed how the different feedback and assessment formats are generated
with R/exams from the same pool of exercise templates.</p>

<!--

Thus, the _learning_ phase is not so unusual:
* _Standard:_ Textbook along with presentation slides.
* _Streaming:_ Videos streamed simultaneously or (pre-)recorded.

But for _feedback_ and _assessment_ the following is required:
* _Scalability:_ Randomized dynamic exercises.
* _Feedback:_ Support for either just the correct answer or the complete approach to the correct solution.
* _Flexibility:_ Automatic rendering into different assessment formats.

[WU Wirtschaftsuniversität Wien](https://www.wu.ac.at/)
Böhm & Strasser, [Mathematik für Wirtschaft und Management](http://mb000041.host.inode.at/f-erstsemfor.php?listNR=1)

-->

<h3 id="exercises">Exercises</h3>

<p>The core of the course are about 400 <a href="/intro/dynamic">dynamic exercise templates</a> where students have to compute some number based on
a problem description or a short story. Some examples from this pool have also been translated into English and included in R/exams, e.g.,
<a href="/templates/deriv/">deriv</a>, <a href="/templates/lagrange/">lagrange</a>, <a href="/templates/hessian/">hessian</a>.
Almost all of these exercises have been established as num exercises first (with numeric result,
employed in online tests) and then <a href="/tutorials/static_num_schoice/">converted to single-choice format</a>
(schoice, see e.g. <a href="/templates/deriv2/">deriv2</a>) as this format can be easily scanned automatically in
<a href="/intro/written/">written exams</a>. Additionally, there are about 70 dynamic multiple-choice questions
(mchoice) that are used either in online tests or live quizzes.</p>

<p>As illustrated in the following, these exercises are the thread running through the enitre course, starting with
the lecture slides where typically one static snapshot from an exercise is used (potentially with
some additional explanations, incremental slides, graphics, etc.) Below
we show screenshots from such a curve sketching exercise in the screencasts (based on the slides).
It depicts a simple cubic polynomial of type <em>a x<sup>3</sup> + b x<sup>2</sup> + c x + d</em>
for which the two local optima and the inflection point have to be found.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/screencast1.png"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/screencast1-thumb.png" alt="screencast1.png" /></a>
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/screencast2.png"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/screencast2-thumb.png" alt="screencast2.png" /></a></p>

<h3 id="online-test">Online test</h3>

<p>The corresponding dynamic exercise templates can then be used in an online test.
In fact, here there are three dynamic templates that draw different coefficients <em>a</em>, <em>b</em>, <em>c</em>,
and <em>d</em> and either ask for the function value <em>f(x)</em> in one of the local optima (A or C), or the
second derivative <em>f’‘(x)</em> in one of the local optima (A or C), or the slope <em>f’(x)</em> in the
inflection point B.</p>

<p>In the screenshots below the second derivative <em>f’‘(x)</em> in C is demanded, but the argument <em>x</em>
is C incorrectly entered/saved by the student, prompting OpenOLAT to display the full correct approach to the solution.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/onlinetest1.png"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/onlinetest1-thumb.png" alt="onlinetest1.png" /></a>
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/onlinetest2.png"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/onlinetest2-thumb.png" alt="onlinetest2.png" /></a></p>

<p>To import an online test into OpenOLAT, an XML-based exchange format by the IMS Global Learning Consortium is used:
<a href="http://www.imsglobal.org/question/qtiv1p2/imsqti_asi_bindv1p2.html">IMS Question &amp; Test Interoperability, Version 1.2</a> (QTI 1.2).
The R/exams function <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2qti12()</code> generates a zipped XML file
that can be imported into OpenOLAT as a complete online test. To do so
we first set up a list of exercises à la:</p>

<pre><code class="language-{r}">otest &lt;- list(
  c("deriv-poly.Rnw", "deriv-sqrt.Rnw", "deriv-exp.Rnw", ...),
  c("graph-deriv-A.Rnw", "graph-deriv-B.Rnw", "graph-deriv-C.Rnw"),
  ...
)
</code></pre>

<p>And then <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2qti12()</code> can proceed to draw many replications from this combining two forms of
randomization: (a) Sampling one item from a given vector of exercise templates (e.g., here
the <code class="highlighter-rouge">deriv-*.Rnw</code> templates for the first item). (b) In each <code class="highlighter-rouge">.Rnw</code> template random
numbers are drawn and inserted into the exercise (e.g., the coefficients <em>a</em>, <em>b</em>, <em>c</em>, <em>d</em>
in the cubic polynomial). For example:</p>

<pre><code class="language-{r}">exams2qti12(otest, n = 500, name = "Mathematik-Onlinetest-01", 
  solutionswitch = FALSE, maxattempts = 2, cutvalue = 1000)
</code></pre>

<p>draws 500 random versions for each of the items in the test. We don’t
show the correct solution approach at the end (only the correct numeric result, <code class="highlighter-rouge">solutionswitch = FALSE</code>)
but allow our students to attempt each item within the test twice (i.e., one wrong attempt is
tolerated). Because individual tests cannot be passed or failed (they just collect points for
the overall course), we set <code class="highlighter-rouge">cutvalue = 1000</code> which can never be attained. Due to the large
exercise pools and the large number of random variations, the students cannot simply copy
a single number or a certain solution formula. Of course, during a 3.5-day test it is possible
to help each other and in fact we encourage the students to form small learning groups.</p>

<p>Further control arguments of <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2qti12()</code> include the number of <code class="highlighter-rouge">points</code> and the <code class="highlighter-rouge">eval</code> strategy (e.g., 
for negative points upon incorrect results etc.). See <code class="highlighter-rouge">?exams2qti</code> for more technical
details and also for an example you can run yourself based on exercises from the 
<a href="/templates/">template gallery</a>.</p>

<p>In addition to the online tests (= assessment) we employ self tests (= feedback), either in the
form of selected demo exercises (“Musteraufgaben”) for which the full solution approach is shown
(<code class="highlighter-rouge">solutionswitch = TRUE</code>), short tests that sample exercises from almost the entire exercise
pool (“Selbsttests”), or “mock exams” based on past written exams (“Probeklausuren”).</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: left">Course element <br />  </th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Item <br /> type</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Templates <br /> per item</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Full <br /> solution</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Show points <br /> during test?</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Time <br /> (min.)</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Attempts <br /> per item</th>
      <th style="text-align: center">Attempts <br /> per test</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Purpose <br />  </th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left"><strong>Online test</strong></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">num or <br /> mchoice</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">3-20</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"> </td>
      <td style="text-align: center">x</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"> </td>
      <td style="text-align: center">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Assessment <br /> during semester</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left"><strong>Demo exercises</strong> <br /> (Musteraufgaben)</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">num or <br /> mchoice</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">x</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">x</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"> </td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">∞</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Feedback <br /> after lecture</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left"><strong>Self test</strong>      <br /> (Selbsttest)</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">schoice</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">3-20</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"> </td>
      <td style="text-align: center">x</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"> </td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">∞</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Feedback <br /> during semester</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: left"><strong>Mock exam</strong>      <br /> (Probeklausur)</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">schoice</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: center"> </td>
      <td style="text-align: center"> </td>
      <td style="text-align: center">90</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">∞</td>
      <td style="text-align: center">∞</td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Feedback <br /> before exam</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>As the written exams use single-choice versions of the exercises, the latter two test types 
also practice using this item type (see the screenshot below).</p>

<p><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/onlinetest3.png"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/onlinetest3-thumb.png" alt="onlinetest3.png" /></a></p>

<h3 id="written-exam">Written exam</h3>

<p>The course ends in a “strict” written exam (“Gesamtprüfung”) in the sense that now each student really
has to solve his/her own exam without further help in a time window of 90 minutes.
The function employed for generating the PDF files is <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2nops()</code> and its usage
is illustrated in detail in the tutorial on <a href="/tutorials/exams2nops/">written exams</a>.</p>

<p>First, a <em>vector</em> (as opposed to a <em>list</em>) of exercises is set up à la:</p>

<pre><code class="language-{r}">gp &lt;- c(
  "deriv-sqrt.Rnw",
  "graph-deriv-B.Rnw",
  ...
)
</code></pre>

<p>Thus, for written exams we assure that every student gets the same exercise template,
only with some random variations of the numbers/graphics/etc. Thus, we try to make the
exam as fair as possible while assuring that cheating is very hard. If there are, say,
400 participants in the exam, there are 400 different exams with single-choice
exercises. These can be generated (typically after setting a random seed for reproducibility)
via:</p>

<pre><code class="language-{r}">set.seed(2017-04-05)
exams2nops(gp, n = 400, name = "GP", title = "GP Mathematik",
  institution = "Universit\\\"at Innsbruck", logo = "uibk-logo-bw.png",
  language = "de", course = "403100--200", date = "2017-04-05", reglength = 7,
  pages = c("/path/to/formulary.pdf", "/path/to/normal-table.pdf"))
</code></pre>

<p>Thus, in addition to some information about course/exam, we specify the language (German), length of the registration
ID (7 digits), and add PDF pages with the formulary and normal tables.
The first few pages of one of the resulting PDFs are displayed below. More details on the
evaluation process can be found in the <a href="/tutorials/exams2nops/">exams2nops</a> tutorial.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/nops1.png"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/nops1-thumb.png" alt="nops1.png" /></a>
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/nops2.png"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/nops2-thumb.png" alt="nops2.png" /></a>
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/nops3.png"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/nops3-thumb.png" alt="nops3.png" /></a></p>

<p>A very nice benefit of using R/exams here is that we can share an interactive online
“mock exam” (“Probeklausur”) in addition to the PDF version in the exam archive. This
can again be generated by <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2qti12()</code> with time limit and evaluation settings
corresponding to the actual written exam:</p>

<pre><code class="language-{r}">exams2qti12(gp, n = 10, name = "Mathematik-GP-2017-04-05",
  maxattempts = Inf, cutvalue = 18, solutionswitch = FALSE,
  points = 2, eval = list(partial = FALSE, negative = -0.25),
  duration = 90)
</code></pre>

<p>The screen shots below show first the interactive version of the mock exam and then
one of the PDFs in the resources archive.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/mockexam1.png"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/mockexam1-thumb.png" alt="mockexam1.png" /></a>
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/mockexam2.png"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/mockexam2-thumb.png" alt="mockexam2.png" /></a></p>

<h3 id="live-quiz">Live quiz</h3>

<p>Finally, the same exercise templates can also be imported into live quizzes when the
audience response system ARSnova is used (see <a href="https://arsnova.eu/">https://arsnova.eu/</a>). As we do not use
the system for assessment but only for feedback it is not as important to have a lot
of random variation in the exercises, but it certainly helps to avoid duplication
across courses taught in parallel or in subsequent semesters.
Moreover, the R/exams function <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2arsnova()</code> can directly import the drawn exercises
into ARSnova using its REST interface (via Rcurl and suitable JSON data). Alternatively,
JSON files can be generated on the hard disk and subsequently imported manually.</p>

<p>As an illustration we use again a vector of exercise templates and export random
draws from these directly into a previously-generated ARSnova session (using one
session for the enitre semester). Authentication can be done through the JSESSIONID.</p>

<pre><code class="language-{r}">quiz &lt;- c("deriv-sqrt.Rnw", "graph-deriv-B.Rnw", ...)
exams2arsnova(quiz, name = "Quiz", url = "https://arsnova.uibk.ac.at",
  sessionkey = "79732490", jsessionid = "34A6B8C1D83CB7D0EC66F14DA7044DB1",
  fix_choice = FALSE, abstention = FALSE)
</code></pre>

<p>The students can then view the exercises on the mobile phones or tablets, practicing for
the exam, followed by a phase of peer instruction to resolve remaining problems.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/arsnova1.png"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/arsnova1-thumb.png" alt="arsnova1.png" /></a>
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/arsnova2.png"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-11-07-uibk_math/arsnova2-thumb.png" alt="arsnova2.png" /></a></p>

<p>Exercises like shown in the two screenshots above are used for exam practice during lecture
or tutorial sessions. Additionally, knowledge quiz questions
are frequently used for checking whether the students can follow the lecture or not.
These are typically in the form of multiple-choice questions where each subitem can either be
true or false. See <a href="/templates/gaussmarkov/">gaussmarkov</a> for a worked example.</p>

<h3 id="summary">Summary</h3>

<p>This blog post has shown how the same pool of exercises can be used flexibly for
different elements of a large-lecture course. Over the last years we experimented
quite a bit with these and kept those elements we (or the students) found useful
but discontinued using others. Of course, the hard part is establishing the large
exercise pool but then R/exams enables us to try out different formats fairly easily.</p>

<p>If you have further questions about these tools or want to let us know how you
use R/exams in your course, please get in touch! Either via
<a href="/contact/">our forum, StackOverflow, Twitter, or simply by e-mail</a>.</p>

    ]]></description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.R-exams.org/general/uibk_math/</guid>
			</item>
		
    
    
			<item>
        <title><![CDATA[From Static to Numeric to Single-Choice Exercises in R/exams]]></title>
				<link>http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/static_num_schoice/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <description><![CDATA[
    
    <p>Tutorial for turning a static arithmetic exercise into a dynamic numeric exercise template and furthermore into a dynamic single-choice exercise template.</p>
    
    
    <p><img alt="From Static to Numeric to Single-Choice Exercises in R/exams" src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/elasticity.title.jpg" /></p>
    
    <h2 id="idea">Idea</h2>

<p>Our colleagues over at the economics department became interested in using <a href="http://www.R-exams.org">R/exams</a> for
generating large-scale exams in their introductory economics courses. However, they face the challenge that
so far they had been writing static exercises and modified them <em>by hand</em> if they wanted to reuse them in a
different exam in another semester. To let R/exams do this job it is illustrated how a static arithmetic
exercise can be turned into a <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/intro/dynamic/">dynamic exercise template</a> either in <code class="highlighter-rouge">num</code>
format with a numeric solution or into <code class="highlighter-rouge">schoice</code> format with a single-choice solution.
The idea for the exercise is a very basic <em>price elasticity of demand</em> task:</p>

<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Consider the following inverse demand function: <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mrow><mi>p</mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mi>x</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mo>=</mo><mi>a</mi><mo>-</mo><mi>b</mi><mo>&middot;</mo><mi>x</mi></mrow></math> for the price <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mrow><mi>p</mi></mrow></math> given the demanded quantity <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mrow><mi>x</mi></mrow></math>. What is the price elastiticy of demand at a price of <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mrow><mi>p</mi></mrow></math>?</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>The natural candidates for “parameterizing” this exercise are the
price <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mrow><mi>p</mi></mrow></math>
and the parameters <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mrow><mi>a</mi></mrow></math>
and <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mrow><mi>b</mi></mrow></math> of the inverse demand function.
Based on these the solution is simply:</p>

<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>First, we obtain the demand function by inverting the inverse demand function: <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mrow><mi>x</mi><mo>=</mo><mi>D</mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mi>p</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mo>=</mo><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mi>a</mi><mo>-</mo><mi>p</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo><mo stretchy="false">/</mo><mi>b</mi></mrow></math>. <br /> Then, at <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mrow><mi>p</mi></mrow></math> the price elasticity of demand is <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mstyle displaystyle="true"><mrow><mfrac><mrow><mi>D</mi><mo>'</mo><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mi>p</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow><mrow><mi>D</mi><mo stretchy="false">(</mo><mi>p</mi><mo stretchy="false">)</mo></mrow></mfrac><mi>p</mi><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mo>-</mo><mn>1</mn><mo stretchy="false">/</mo><mi>b</mi></mrow><mrow><mi>x</mi></mrow></mfrac><mi>p</mi><mo>.</mo></mrow></mstyle></math></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>

<p>Below various incarnations of this exercise are provided in both R/Markdown <code class="highlighter-rouge">Rmd</code> and R/LaTeX <code class="highlighter-rouge">Rnw</code> format.
The following table gives a brief overview of all available versions along with a short description of the idea behind it.
More detailed explanations are provided in the subsequent sections.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: right">#</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Exercise templates</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Dynamic?</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Type</th>
      <th style="text-align: left">Description</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: right">1</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity1.Rmd">elasticity1.Rmd</a> <br /> <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity1.Rnw">elasticity1.Rnw</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">No</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"><code class="highlighter-rouge">num</code></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Fixed parameters and numeric solution.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: right">2</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity2.Rmd">elasticity2.Rmd</a> <br /> <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity2.Rnw">elasticity2.Rnw</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">No</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"><code class="highlighter-rouge">schoice</code></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">As in #1 but with single-choice solution (five answer alternatives).</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: right">3</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity3.Rmd">elasticity3.Rmd</a> <br /> <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity3.Rnw">elasticity3.Rnw</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Yes</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"><code class="highlighter-rouge">num</code></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Randomly drawn parameters with dynamic computation of correct solution, based on #1.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: right">4</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity4.Rmd">elasticity4.Rmd</a> <br /> <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity4.Rnw">elasticity4.Rnw</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Yes</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"><code class="highlighter-rouge">schoice</code></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Randomly drawn parameters (as in #3) with dynamically-generated single-choice solution (as in #2), computed by <code class="highlighter-rouge">num_to_schoice()</code>.</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: right">5</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity5.Rmd">elasticity5.Rmd</a> <br /> <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity5.Rnw">elasticity5.Rnw</a></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">Yes</td>
      <td style="text-align: left"><code class="highlighter-rouge">schoice</code></td>
      <td style="text-align: left">As in #4 but with the last alternative: <em>None of the above.</em></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="static-numeric">Static numeric</h2>

<p>The starting point is a completely static exercise as it had been used in a previous
introductory economics exam. The parameters had been set
to <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mrow><mi>p</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>5</mn></mrow></math>, <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mrow><mi>a</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>50</mn></mrow></math>, 
and <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mrow><mi>b</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>0</mn><mo>.</mo><mn>5</mn></mrow></math>.
This implies that <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mrow><mi>x</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>90</mn></mrow></math>,
leading to an elasticity of <math xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"><mrow><mo>-</mo><mn>0</mn><mo>.</mo><mn>111111</mn></mrow></math>.</p>

<p>The corresponding R/exams templates simply hard-code these numbers into the question/solution
and wrap everything into R/Markdown (<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity1.Rmd">elasticity1.Rmd</a>)
or R/LaTeX (<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity1.Rnw">elasticity1.Rnw</a>).
Note that LaTeX is used in either case for the mathematical notation. In case you are unfamiliar
with the R/exams format, please check out the <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/first_steps/">First Steps</a> tutorial.</p>

<p>The meta-information simply sets <code class="highlighter-rouge">extype</code> to <code class="highlighter-rouge">num</code>, supplies the <code class="highlighter-rouge">exsolution</code> with a precision of three digits,
and allows an <code class="highlighter-rouge">extol</code> tolerance of 0.01. To see what the result looks like download the files linked above
and run <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2html()</code> and/or <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2pdf()</code>. (The examples below always use the R/Markdown version but the
R/LaTeX version can be used in exactly the same way.)</p>

<pre>
library("exams")
exams2html("elasticity1.Rmd")
exams2pdf("elasticity1.Rmd")
</pre>

<h2 id="static-single-choice">Static single-choice</h2>

<p>Single-choice versions of exercises are often desired for use in <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/intro/written/">written exams</a>
because they can be conveniently scanned and automatically evaluated. Thus, we need to come up
with a number of incorrect alternative solutions (or “distractors”). If desired, these could include
typical wrong solutions or a <em>None of the others</em> alternative.</p>

<p>The R/exams templates
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity2.Rmd">elasticity2.Rmd</a> and
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity2.Rnw">elasticity2.Rnw</a> are
essentially copies of the static numeric exercise above but:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Question/solution now contain an answerlist (with five alternatives).</li>
  <li>The <code class="highlighter-rouge">extype</code> has been changed to <code class="highlighter-rouge">schoice</code>.</li>
  <li>The <code class="highlighter-rouge">exsolution</code> now contains a binary coding of the correct solution.</li>
  <li>Furthermore, to obtain some basic randomization we have turned on shuffling by setting <code class="highlighter-rouge">exshuffle</code>
to <code class="highlighter-rouge">TRUE</code>. (Subsampling more than five alternatives would also be possible and would add some further randomization.)</li>
</ol>

<p>As above <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2html()</code> and/or <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2pdf()</code> can be used to display the exercise interactively in R/exams.</p>

<h2 id="dynamic-numeric">Dynamic numeric</h2>

<p>Next, the static exercise from above is made dynamic by drawing the parameters from a suitable
data-generating process. In this case, the following works well:</p>

<pre>
## p = a - b * x
p &lt;- sample(5:15, 1)
fctr &lt;- sample(c(2, 4, 5, 10), 1)
x &lt;- sample(5:15, 1) * fctr
b &lt;- sample(1:5, 1) / fctr
a &lt;- p + b * x

## elasticity
sol &lt;- -1/b * p/x
</pre>

<p>Note that in order to obtain “nice” numbers a common scaling factor <code class="highlighter-rouge">fctr</code> is used for both <code class="highlighter-rouge">x</code> and <code class="highlighter-rouge">b</code>.
Also, while the examinees are presented with parameters <code class="highlighter-rouge">a</code> and <code class="highlighter-rouge">b</code> and have to compute <code class="highlighter-rouge">x</code>,
the data-generating process actually draws <code class="highlighter-rouge">x</code> and <code class="highlighter-rouge">b</code> and computes <code class="highlighter-rouge">a</code> from that. Again, this makes it
easier to obtain “nice” numbers.</p>

<p>The R/exams templates
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity3.Rmd">elasticity3.Rmd</a> and
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity3.Rnw">elasticity3.Rnw</a> include
the data-generating process above as a code chunk either in R/Markdown or R/LaTeX format.
The parameters are then inserted into question/solution/metainformation using <code class="prettyprint ">`r a`</code> (R/Markdown)
or <code class="highlighter-rouge">\Sexpr{a}</code> (R/LaTeX). Sometimes the <code class="highlighter-rouge">fmt()</code> function is used for formatting the parameters
with a desired number of digits. (See <code class="highlighter-rouge">?fmt</code> for more details.)</p>

<p>As before <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2html()</code> and/or <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2pdf()</code> can be used to display the <em>random draws</em> from
the exercise templates. For checking that the meta-information is included correctly, it is often
helpful to run</p>

<pre>
exams_metainfo(exams2html("elasticity3.Rmd"))
</pre>

<p>Furthermore, some tweaking is usually required when calibrating the parameter ranges in the
data-generating process. The <code class="highlighter-rouge">stresstest_exercise()</code> function draws a large number of random replications
and thus can help to spot errors that occur or to find solutions that are “extreme” (e.g., much larger or smaller than usual). To clean up your
global environment and run the function use something like this:</p>

<pre>
rm(list = ls())
s &lt;- stresstest_exercise("elasticity3.Rmd", n = 200)
plot(s)
plot(s, type = "solution")
</pre>

<p>The latter command plots the correct solution against the (scalar) parameters that were
generated in the exercise. This might show patterns for which parameters the solution becomes
too large or too small etc. See <code class="highlighter-rouge">?stresstest_exercise</code> for further features/details.</p>

<h2 id="dynamic-single-choice">Dynamic single-choice</h2>

<p>To go from the dynamic numeric exercise to a dynamic single-choice exercise we need to
extend the data-generating process to also produce a number of wrong alternatives.
The function <code class="highlighter-rouge">num_to_schoice()</code> helps with this by providing different sampling
mechanisms. It allows to set a range in which the alternatives have to be, a minimum
distance between all alternatives, possibly include typical wrong solutions, etc.
It also shuffles the resulting alternatives and tries to make sure that the correct
solution is <em>not</em> a certain order statistic (e.g., almost always the largest or
smallest alternative).</p>

<p>The R/exams templates
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity4.Rmd">elasticity4.Rmd</a> and
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity4.Rnw">elasticity4.Rnw</a> first
wrap the data-generating process into a while loop with <code class="highlighter-rouge">while(sol &gt; -0.11)</code>. This makes sure
that there is enough “space” for four wrong alternatives between -0.11 and 0, using a minimum
distance of 0.017. Subsequently, the four wrong alternatives are generated by:</p>

<pre>
## single-choice incl. typical errors
err &lt;- c(1/sol, sol/p, p/sol)
err &lt;- err[(err &gt; -5) &amp; (err &lt; -0.2) &amp; abs(err - sol) &gt; 0.01]
rng &lt;- c(min(1.5 * sol, -1), -0.01)
sc &lt;- num_to_schoice(sol, wrong = err, range = rng,
  delta = 0.017, method = "delta", digits = 3)
</pre>

<p>This suggests a number of typical wrong solutions <code class="highlighter-rouge">err</code> (provided that they are not too small
or too large) and makes sure that the range <code class="highlighter-rouge">rng</code> is large enough. With these arguments
<code class="highlighter-rouge">num_to_schoice()</code> is run, see <code class="highlighter-rouge">?num_to_schoice</code> for the details. The resulting <code class="highlighter-rouge">sc</code> list
contains suitable <code class="highlighter-rouge">$questions</code> and <code class="highlighter-rouge">$solutions</code> that can be easily embedded in an <code class="highlighter-rouge">answerlist()</code>
and in the meta-information. Sometimes it is useful to wrap <code class="highlighter-rouge">num_to_schoice()</code> into another
<code class="highlighter-rouge">while()</code> loop to make sure a valid result is found. See the <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/templates/deriv2/">deriv2</a>
template for illustraion.</p>

<p>As before <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2html()</code> and/or <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2pdf()</code> can be used to display the <em>random draws</em> from
this exercise template. And some stress-testing could be carried out by:</p>

<pre>
rm(list = ls())
s &lt;- stresstest_exercise("elasticity4.Rmd", n = 200)
plot(s)
plot(s, type = "ordering")
</pre>

<p>As a final variation we could include <em>None of the above</em> as the last alternative. This is
very easy because we can simply replace the fifth element of the question list with the corresponding
string:</p>

<pre>
sc$questions[5] &lt;- "None of the above."
</pre>

<p>No matter whether this was actually the correct alternative or one of the incorrect alternatives, the
corresponding solution will stay the same. The R/exams templates
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity5.Rmd">elasticity5.Rmd</a> and
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-10-07-static_num_schoice/elasticity5.Rnw">elasticity5.Rnw</a> incorporate
this additional line of code in the data-generating process.</p>


    ]]></description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/static_num_schoice/</guid>
			</item>
		
    
    
			<item>
        <title><![CDATA[Welcome to R/exams]]></title>
				<link>http://www.R-exams.org/general/welcome/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <description><![CDATA[
    
    <p>Brief introduction to the new web page and blog of the R/exams project.</p>
    
    
    <p><img alt="Welcome to R/exams" src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/rexams_carousel.title.jpg" /></p>
    
    <p>Welcome everybody, we are proud to introduce the brand new web page and
blog <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/">http://www.R-exams.org/</a>. This provides a central access point for
the <a href="/resources/">open-source software “exams”</a> implemented in the
<a href="https://www.R-project.org/">R</a> system for statistical computing.
R/exams is a one-for-all exams generator using (potentially) dynamic
exercises written in R/Markdown or R/LaTeX and it can export a variety of
formats from learning management systems to classical written exams.
This post gives a brief overview of what has happened so far and what
you can expect to find here in the next months.</p>

<div class="row t20 b20">
  <div class="small-12 medium-10 medium-offset-1 large-8 large-offset-2 columns">
    <img src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/oneforall_logo.svg" alt="oneforall" width="970px" />
  </div>
</div>

<h4 id="past">Past</h4>

<p>The package was originally started more than a decade ago to facilitate
classical written exams with randomized exercises for large-lecture courses.
Like many other teachers of introductory statistics and mathematics courses,
we were in need of infrastructure for conducting written exams with about 1,000-1,500
students. A team effort of colleagues at WU Wirtschaftsuniversität Wien
lead to a large collection of dynamic exercises and the software was eventually
released at <a href="https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=exams">https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=exams</a>.</p>

<p>Over the years learning management systems (like
<a href="https://www.moodle.org/">Moodle</a>,
<a href="http://www.blackboard.com/">Blackboard</a>,
<a href="https://www.openolat.com/">OLAT</a>, etc.)
became easily available at virtually every university, creating a desire to
employ the same dynamic exercises also for online tests and quizzes. Hence,
the R/exams infrastructure was completely reimplemented allowing to export
the same exercises not only to written exams (with automatic scanning
and evaluation) but also to learning management systems, the live voting
system <a href="https://www.arsnova.eu/">ARSnova</a>, as well as customizable standalone
files in PDF, HTML, Docx, and beyond.</p>

<p>Despite (or rather because of) the flexibility of the software, novice R/exams
users often struggled with adopting it because the documentation provided in
the package is either somewhat technical and/or targeted towards more experienced
R users.</p>

<h4 id="present">Present</h4>

<p>Hence, this web page and blog make it easy for new users to explore the possibilities
of R/exams before reading about a lot of technical details. It also provides accessible
guides to common tasks and examples for dynamic exercises with different complexity.
For a first tour you can check out the <a href="/intro/oneforall">one-for-all approach</a> of
the package based on (potentially) <a href="/intro/dynamic">dynamic exercise templates</a>
for generating large numbers of personalized exams/quizzes/tests, either for
<a href="/intro/elearning">e-learning</a> or classical <a href="/intro/written">written exams</a> (with
automatic evaluation).</p>

<p>Some <a href="/tutorials/">tutorials</a> already explain the installation of R/exams (with
dependencies like LaTeX or pandoc) and the first steps in writing dynamic exercises
using either Markdown or LaTeX markup along with randomization in R. There is
also a <a href="/templates/">gallery of exercise templates</a>, ranging from basic multiple-choice
questions with simple shuffling to more advanced exercises with random data, graphics,
etc.</p>

<h4 id="future">Future</h4>

<p>For the next months we plan to write more tutorial blog posts that help to accomplish
common tasks, e.g., hands-on guidance for exporting exercises from R to Moodle or
tips how to write good randomized exercises. If you want to give us feedback or ask
us to cover certain topics please feel free to <a href="/contact/">contact us</a> - be it via e-mail,
discussion forum, or twitter. Also if you want to link R/exams-based materials or share
share experiences of using R/exams in a guest post, please let us know.</p>

<h4 id="thanks">Thanks</h4>

<p>Big shout to all <a href="/contact/#authors-and-contributors">contributors</a> that helped R/exams to grow so much
over the last years. A special thank you goes to Patrik Keller, Hanna Krimm, and Reto
Stauffer who established the infrastructure for this web page (using R/Markdown and Jekyll)
and designed graphics/icons/photos/etc. Thanks also to everyone sharing this post,
especially on <a href="http://www.R-bloggers.com/">http://www.R-bloggers.com/</a> and <a href="https://RWeekly.org/">https://RWeekly.org/</a>.</p>

    ]]></description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.R-exams.org/general/welcome/</guid>
			</item>
		
    
    
			<item>
        <title><![CDATA[Written Multiple-Choice Exams with R/exams]]></title>
				<link>http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/exams2nops/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <description><![CDATA[
    
    <p>Step-by-step guide to generating, conducting, scanning, and automatically evaluating large-scale written exams with exams2nops() in R/exams.</p>
    
    
    <p><img alt="Written Multiple-Choice Exams with R/exams" src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/olympia_front.title.jpg" /></p>
    
    <h2 id="create-exam">Create exam</h2>

<div class="row t20 b20">
  <div class="small-8 medium-9 columns">

<p>The first step in conducting a <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/intro/written/">written exam</a> with multiple-choice
(and/or single-choice) exercises in R/exams' NOPS format is to create the exam in PDF format.
First, we load the R <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams</code> package and then simply create a list of exercise file names.</p>

  </div>
  <div class="small-4 medium-3 columns">
    <img src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/written-create.svg" alt="create" />
  </div>
</div>

<pre><code class="prettyprint ">library(&quot;exams&quot;)
myexam &lt;- list(
  &quot;tstat2.Rnw&quot;,
  &quot;ttest.Rnw&quot;,
  &quot;relfreq.Rnw&quot;,
  &quot;anova.Rnw&quot;,
  c(&quot;boxplots.Rnw&quot;, &quot;scatterplot.Rnw&quot;),
  &quot;cholesky.Rnw&quot;
)</code></pre>

<p>Here, we use a number of <code class="highlighter-rouge">schoice</code> and <code class="highlighter-rouge">mchoice</code> questions that are directly shipped
within the package. In practice, you would use files that you have authored and stored
somewhere locally. Above, exercises in .Rnw format are used but all of the examples
are also available in .Rmd format, leading to virtually identical output.</p>

<p>Then, we create a small exam with only <code class="highlighter-rouge">n = 2</code> randomly-drawn versions, storing the
resulting PDF files (plus metainformation) on the disk in a new output directory <code class="highlighter-rouge">nops_pdf</code>.
To customize the exam we assign a different number of points to the different exercises
and also show the respective number of points at the beginning of each question.</p>

<pre><code class="prettyprint ">set.seed(403)
ex1 &lt;- exams2nops(myexam, n = 2,
  dir = &quot;nops_pdf&quot;, name = &quot;demo&quot;, date = &quot;2015-07-29&quot;,
  points = c(1, 1, 1, 2, 2, 3), showpoints = TRUE)</code></pre>

<p>A random seed is set to make the generated exams exactly reproducible for you
(or ourselves at some point in the future). The output directory now contains three files
that were generated.</p>

<pre><code class="prettyprint ">dir(&quot;nops_pdf&quot;)</code></pre>

<pre><code>## [1] &quot;demo.rds&quot;  &quot;demo1.pdf&quot; &quot;demo2.pdf&quot;
</code></pre>

<p>The two PDF files are the two exams we requested above.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-18-exams2nops//demo1.pdf"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-18-exams2nops/demo1.png" alt="demo1.pdf" /></a>
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-18-exams2nops//demo2.pdf"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-18-exams2nops/demo2.png" alt="demo2.pdf" /></a></p>

<p>Furthermore, the metainfromation about the exam (exam IDs, questions, correct and wrong
answer alternatives) is stored in a <code class="highlighter-rouge">demo.rds</code> file (serialized R data). This crucial
for being able to evaluate the exam later on.</p>

<h2 id="print-pdf-files">Print PDF files</h2>

<div class="row t20">
  <div class="small-8 medium-9 columns">

<ul>
  <li>A small number of exams can easily be printed on a standard printer.
    Otherwise simply use a print shop.</li>
  <li>It is recommended <em>not</em> to scale the printout (i.e., without "Fit to printable area")
    and to staple the exams in the top-left corner.</li>
  <li>By default the PDFs from <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2nops()</code> have a blank second page for
    duplex printing (without content on the back of the exam sheet). For non-duplex printing
    simply set <code class="highlighter-rouge">duplex = FALSE</code> when creating the PDFs
    with <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2nops()</code>.</li>
</ul>

  </div>
  <div class="small-4 medium-3 columns">
    <img src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/written-print.svg" alt="print" />
  </div>
</div>

<h2 id="conduct-exam">Conduct exam</h2>

<div class="row t20">
  <div class="small-8 medium-9 columns">

<p>The exam is conducted as usual. But if you used the possibilities of
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/intro/dynamic/">dynamic exercises</a>
in R/exams, the risk of cheating is greatly reduced.

At the end of the exam you just need to collect the completed exam sheet (first page).
Of course, you can also collect the rest of the exam papers (e.g., to keep future students from
seeing the exercises). However, an advantage of letting the students keep their exercises
reduces the need of having post-exam reviews etc.</p>

  </div>
  <div class="small-4 medium-3 columns">
    <img src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/written-exam.svg" alt="exam" />
  </div>
</div>

<h2 id="scan-results">Scan results</h2>

<div class="row t20 b20">
  <div class="small-8 medium-9 columns">

<p>Each completed exam sheet has information on the exam ID, student ID, and the
checked answers. This needs to be scanned into images (PDF or PNG) and can then
be processed by <code class="highlighter-rouge">nops_scan()</code>.

Typically, it's easy to use the photocopiers provided by your university to scan
all sheets into PDF or PNG files. For example, our university provides us with
Canon ImageRunners and the sheet feeder can easily take about 40-50 sheets and
render them into a single PDF file.</p>

  </div>
  <div class="small-4 medium-3 columns">
    <img src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/written-scan.svg" alt="scan" />
  </div>
</div>

<p>Practical recommendations:</p>

<ul>
  <li>The scanned images become smaller in size if the images are read in just black/white
(or grayscale). This may sometimes even facilitate extracting the information (see below).</li>
  <li>If the exams were stapled in the top-left corner (see above) the sheet feeder often
works better if the sheets are rotated by 180 degrees (so that the damaged corner
is not fed first into the machine). This often improves the scanning results
considerably and can be accomodated by setting <code class="highlighter-rouge">rotate = TRUE</code> in <code class="highlighter-rouge">nops_scan()</code>
below.</li>
</ul>

<p>For demonstration, we use two completed demo sheets that are provided along with
the <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams</code> package and copy them to a dedicated directory <code class="highlighter-rouge">nops_scan</code>.</p>

<pre><code class="prettyprint ">img &lt;- dir(system.file(&quot;nops&quot;, package = &quot;exams&quot;), pattern = &quot;nops_scan&quot;,
  full.names = TRUE)
dir.create(&quot;nops_scan&quot;)
file.copy(img, to = &quot;nops_scan&quot;)</code></pre>

<p><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-18-exams2nops//nops_scan1.png"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-18-exams2nops/nops_scan1-thumb.png" alt="nops_scan1.png" /></a>
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-18-exams2nops//nops_scan2.png"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-18-exams2nops/nops_scan2-thumb.png" alt="nops_scan2.png" /></a></p>

<p>(Note that the first scanned image corresponds to one of the PDFs above while
the other one was generated with custom title/logo/language/etc.)</p>

<p>Using the function <code class="highlighter-rouge">nops_scan()</code> we can now read all scanned images (i.e.,
all locally available PNG and/or PDF files) and collect everything in a ZIP file.
(Note that if there were PDF files that need to be scanned, then the
PDF toolkit <code class="highlighter-rouge">pdftk</code> and the function <code class="highlighter-rouge">convert</code> from ImageMagick need to be
available outside of R on the command line.)</p>

<pre><code class="prettyprint ">nops_scan(dir = &quot;nops_scan&quot;)</code></pre>

<pre><code class="prettyprint ">dir(&quot;nops_scan&quot;)</code></pre>

<pre><code>## [1] &quot;nops_scan_20170810004404.zip&quot; &quot;nops_scan1.png&quot;              
## [3] &quot;nops_scan2.png&quot;
</code></pre>

<p>The resulting file <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-18-exams2nops//nops_scan_20170810004404.zip">nops_scan_20170810004404.zip</a> contains copies of the
PNG files along with a file called <code class="highlighter-rouge">Daten.txt</code> (for historical reasons) that
contains the scanned information in machine-readable from.</p>

<p>See <code class="highlighter-rouge">?nops_scan</code> for more details, e.g., multicore support or options for
rotating PDF files prior to scanning.</p>

<h2 id="evaluate-results">Evaluate results</h2>

<div class="row t20 b20">
  <div class="small-8 medium-9 columns">

<p>In the previous scanning step the exam sheets have just been <em>read</em> but not
yet <em>evaluated</em>, i.e., it has not yet been assessed which questions were answered
(partially) correctly and which were wrong, and no points have been assigned.
Therefore, we use <code class="highlighter-rouge">nops_eval()</code> to carry out these computations and to make
the results available - both in a format easy to read for machines (a CSV file)
and a format for humans (one HTML page for each student).</p>

  </div>
  <div class="small-4 medium-3 columns">
    <img src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/written-evaluate.svg" alt="evaluate" />
  </div>
</div>

<p>To do so, three files are required:</p>

<ul>
  <li>An RDS file with the exam meta-information, generated by <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2nops()</code> above.</li>
  <li>A ZIP file with the scanned sheets, generated by <code class="highlighter-rouge">nops_scan()</code> above.</li>
  <li>A CSV file (semicolon-separated values) with the student infomation (registration number, name, and some
ID or username). In practice, this CSV file will typically be processed from some
registration service or learning management system etc. However, here we simply
create a suitable CSV file on the fly.</li>
</ul>

<pre><code class="prettyprint ">write.table(data.frame(
  registration = c(&quot;1501090&quot;, &quot;9901071&quot;),
  name = c(&quot;Jane Doe&quot;, &quot;Ambi Dexter&quot;),
  id = c(&quot;jane_doe&quot;, &quot;ambi_dexter&quot;)
), file = &quot;Exam-2015-07-29.csv&quot;, sep = &quot;;&quot;, quote = FALSE, row.names = FALSE)</code></pre>

<p>The resulting file is <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-18-exams2nops//Exam-2015-07-29.csv">Exam-2015-07-29.csv</a>.</p>

<p>Now the exam can be evaluated creating an output data frame (also stored
as a CSV file) and individual HTML reports (stored in a ZIP file). Here, we
employ an evaluation scheme without partial points in the multiple-choice questions
and differing points across questions.</p>

<pre><code class="prettyprint ">ev1 &lt;- nops_eval(
  register = &quot;Exam-2015-07-29.csv&quot;,
  solutions = &quot;nops_pdf/demo.rds&quot;,
  scans = Sys.glob(&quot;nops_scan/nops_scan_*.zip&quot;),
  eval = exams_eval(partial = FALSE, negative = FALSE),
  interactive = FALSE
)
dir()</code></pre>

<pre><code>## [1] &quot;Exam-2015-07-29.csv&quot; &quot;nops_eval.csv&quot;       &quot;nops_eval.zip&quot;      
## [4] &quot;nops_pdf&quot;            &quot;nops_scan&quot;
</code></pre>

<p>The evaluated data can be inspected by opening <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-18-exams2nops//nops_eval.csv">nops_eval.csv</a> in some spreadsheet
software or we can directly look at the data in R. Based on this information, the marks could be
entered into the university’s information system.</p>

<pre><code class="prettyprint ">ev1</code></pre>

<pre><code>##         registration        name          id        exam scrambling
## 1501090      1501090    Jane Doe    jane_doe 15072900001         00
## 9901071      9901071 Ambi Dexter ambi_dexter 15072900002         00
##                   scan points mark answer.1 solution.1 check.1 points.1
## 1501090 nops_scan1.png      4    5    00100      00100       1        1
## 9901071 nops_scan2.png      0    5    10100      10000       0        0
##         answer.2 solution.2 check.2 points.2 answer.3 solution.3 check.3
## 1501090    11101      11100       0        0    00000      00000       1
## 9901071    10111      11001       0        0    01000      01010       0
##         points.3 answer.4 solution.4 check.4 points.4 answer.5 solution.5
## 1501090        1    00100      00110       0        0    00010      00010
## 9901071        0    00000      01011       0        0    00000      11010
##         check.5 points.5 answer.6 solution.6 check.6 points.6
## 1501090       1        2    01101      01111       0        0
## 9901071       0        0    11100      00011       0        0
</code></pre>

<p>And <code class="highlighter-rouge">nops_eval.zip</code> contains subdirectories with HTML reports for each of the two participants.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-18-exams2nops//Exam-2015-07-29-jane_doe.html"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-18-exams2nops/Exam-2015-07-29-jane_doe.png" alt="Exam-2015-07-29-jane_doe.html" /></a>
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-18-exams2nops//Exam-2015-07-29-ambi_dexter.html"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-18-exams2nops/Exam-2015-07-29-ambi_dexter.png" alt="Exam-2015-07-29-ambi_dexter.html" /></a></p>

<p>These HTML reports could then be uploaded into a learning management system, put on some other
web server, or even sent out via e-mail.</p>

    ]]></description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/exams2nops/</guid>
			</item>
		
    
    
			<item>
        <title><![CDATA[First Steps]]></title>
				<link>http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/first_steps/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <description><![CDATA[
    
    <p>First overview of the structure of R/exams, its exercise templates, and a first hands-on session.</p>
    
    
    <p><img alt="First Steps" src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/laptop_on_table_deriv2.title.jpg" /></p>
    
    <h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>

<p>The basic idea of R/exams is to have a <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/intro/oneforall/">one-for-all exams generator</a>
where each <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/intro/dynamic/">exercise</a> is a standalone file, so that the <em>same</em> exercise can be
rendered easily into a variety output formats such as 
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/intro/elearning/">e-learning systems</a> or
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/intro/written/">written exams</a>. To reduce the risk of cheating,
R/exams offers different mechanisms for drawing random variations of exercises:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Randomly selecting one (or more) out of a set of exercises for each participant.</li>
  <li>Randomly shuffling answer alternatives in single-choice and multiple-choice questions.</li>
  <li>Randomly selecting numbers, text blocks, graphics, etc. using the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/R_(programming_language)">R programming language</a>.</li>
</ul>

<p>Each exercise (or rather “exercise template”) is a standalone file with up to four elements:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Data-generating process in R.</li>
  <li>Question text.</li>
  <li>Solution text.</li>
  <li>Meta-information: Type of question (single-choice, multiple-choice, numeric, string, or combinations thereof),
correct solution, a name/label, etc.</li>
</ol>

<p>Only the question (2) and the meta-information (4) are mandatory while data
generation (1) and solution (3) are optional. Solutions can be used to either
inform teachers about the correct solution for some randomly drawn exercise - 
or for giving students feedback about how to solve a given exercise. Programming
a good data-generating process is often the hardest part of authoring a new
dynamic exercise but is, of course, crucial for drawing a very large number of
random variations.</p>

<p>For formatting the text within question/solution (e.g., italics, bold face, lists, etc.)
two options are available: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown">Markdown</a> or
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LaTeX">LaTeX</a>. The former is very easy to learn
and recommended for authors who do not know LaTeX yet. If mathematic notation and
formulas are needed, then LaTeX can be used - either within a LaTeX or also within
a Markdown question. The file suffix for <a href="http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/">R/Markdown</a>
is <code class="highlighter-rouge">.Rmd</code> while <code class="highlighter-rouge">.Rnw</code> is conventionally used for R/LaTeX, known as
<a href="http://leisch.userweb.mwn.de/Sweave/">Sweave</a>.</p>

<p>In the following, a first session should help new R/exams users to explore the materials
available and get a feeling for the workflow. Furthremore, two
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/templates/">exercise templates</a> are shown in more detail:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/templates/swisscapital/">swisscapital</a>: A static single-choice 
knowledge quiz question where the only randomization is a subsampling of the presented
alternatives.</li>
  <li><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/templates/deriv/">deriv</a>: A dynamic airthmetic question about the
product rule for derivatives where various numbers are drawn randomly in R.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="a-first-session">A first session</h2>

<p>To explore what is available in R/exams two things are necessary: a couple of exercise
templates to draw inspiration from, and some demo R scripts that illustrate how the
different <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2xyz()</code> functions can produce output in a variety of formats. (Here,
<code class="highlighter-rouge">xyz</code> is a <em>placeholder</em> for the output format like <code class="highlighter-rouge">html</code>, <code class="highlighter-rouge">pdf</code>, <code class="highlighter-rouge">moodle</code>, etc.)
The function <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams_skeleton()</code> is a helper function that generates exactly these
materials in a specified folder. For example, when <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams</code> has already been
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/installation/">installed</a>, the following can be carried out
in R:</p>

<pre><code class="prettyprint ">library(&quot;exams&quot;)
exams_skeleton(markup = &quot;markdown&quot;, encoding = &quot;UTF-8&quot;,
  writer = c(&quot;exams2html&quot;, &quot;exams2pdf&quot;, &quot;exams2moodle&quot;))</code></pre>

<p>This copies all R/Markdown files to the current working directory along with demo scripts,
illustrating the usage of <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2html()</code> and <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2pdf()</code> for customizable HTML and
PDF output, respectively, along with Moodle output via <code class="highlighter-rouge">exams2moodle()</code>. Specifically,
the working directory then contains:</p>

<pre><code class="prettyprint ">dir()</code></pre>

<pre><code>## [1] &quot;demo-all.R&quot;    &quot;demo-html.R&quot;   &quot;demo-moodle.R&quot; &quot;demo-pdf.R&quot;   
## [5] &quot;exercises&quot;     &quot;templates&quot;
</code></pre>

<p>Simply open the demo script 
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-10-first_steps//demo-all.R">demo-all.R</a> for the first steps and then continue with
more details in <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-10-first_steps//demo-html.R">demo-html.R</a>, <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-10-first_steps//demo-pdf.R">demo-pdf.R</a>, or
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-09-10-first_steps//demo-moodle.R">demo-moodle.R</a>, respectively.
More information about all the <code class="highlighter-rouge">exercises</code> can be found in the
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/templates/">exercise template gallery</a> online.</p>

<h2 id="single-choice-swiss-capital">Single-choice: Swiss capital</h2>

<p>Knowledge quiz question (about the Swiss capital) with 1 correct and 6 false alternative.
4 out of the 6 false alternatives are sampled randomly and shuffled. Otherwise the
exercise is static and contains no R code. Below the structure of the exercise is
highlighted side-by-side in both <code class="highlighter-rouge">.Rmd</code> and <code class="highlighter-rouge">.Rnw</code>, illustrating that the additional
exercise markup is similar in spirit to the respective typesetting system.</p>

<p>To see what the output looks like, run the following code within R or take a look at
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/templates/swisscapital/">swisscapital</a> in the exercise gallery.</p>

<div class="row t20 b20">
  <div class="small-5 medium-3 large-2 columns">
    <b>Markdown</b><br />
    <img src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/template-rmd.svg" alt="Rmd" />
  </div>
  <div class="small-1 medium-3 large-4 columns">
  <p></p>
  </div>
  <div class="small-5 medium-3 large-2 columns">
    <b>LaTeX</b><br />
    <img src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/template-rnw.svg" alt="Rnw" />
  </div>
  <div class="small-1 medium-3 large-4 columns">
  <p></p>
  </div>
</div>

<div class="row t20 b20">
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <pre>
library("exams")
exams2html("swisscapital.Rmd")
exams2pdf("swisscapital.Rmd")
    </pre>
  </div>
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <pre>
library("exams")
exams2html("swisscapital.Rnw")
exams2pdf("swisscapital.Rnw")
    </pre>
  </div>
</div>

<h4 id="question">Question</h4>

<p>The question is straightforward and lists 7 answer alternatives.
The correct solution (Bern) is declared in the meta-information below.</p>

<div class="row t20 b20">
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <b>Markdown</b>
    <pre>
Question
========
What is the seat of the federal
authorities in Switzerland
(i.e., the de facto capital)?

Answerlist
----------
* Basel
* Bern
* Geneva
* Lausanne
* Zurich
* St. Gallen
* Vaduz
    </pre>
  </div>
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <b>LaTeX</b>
    <pre>

\begin{question}
What is the seat of the federal
authorities in Switzerland
(i.e., the de facto capital)?

\begin{answerlist}
  \item Basel
  \item Bern
  \item Geneva
  \item Lausanne
  \item Zurich
  \item St.~Gallen
  \item Vaduz
\end{answerlist}
\end{question}
    </pre>
  </div>
</div>

<h4 id="solution">Solution</h4>

<p>The optional solution can provide some general feedback (that explains
why Bern is correct in this question) as well as more details for each
answer alternative (only listing true/false here). It is also possible 
to have <em>no solution</em>, or <em>just a general text</em>, or <em>just the answer list</em>.</p>

<div class="row t20 b20">
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <b>Markdown</b>
    <pre>
Solution
========
There is no de jure capital but
the de facto capital and seat of
the federal authorities is Bern.

Answerlist
----------
* False
* True
* False
* False
* False
* False
* False
    </pre>
  </div>
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <b>LaTeX</b>
    <pre>

\begin{solution}
There is no de jure capital but
the de facto capital and seat of
the federal authorities is Bern.

\begin{answerlist}
  \item False.
  \item True.
  \item False.
  \item False.
  \item False.
  \item False.
  \item False.
\end{answerlist}
\end{solution}
    </pre>
  </div>
</div>

<h4 id="meta-information">Meta-information</h4>

<p>In the meta-information, each exercise must specify at least an <code class="highlighter-rouge">extype</code>,
and an <code class="highlighter-rouge">exsolution</code>, and should typically also have a short descriptive
<code class="highlighter-rouge">exname</code>. The type for single-choice questions is <code class="highlighter-rouge">schoice</code> and the
<code class="highlighter-rouge">exsolution</code> is simply a binary coding of the 7 answer alternatives.
For randomization, additionally <code class="highlighter-rouge">exshuffle</code> is set to 5 so that 1 correct
and 4 random wrong alternatives are subsampled and shuffled.</p>

<div class="row t20 b20">
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <b>Markdown</b>
    <pre>
Meta-information
================
exname: Swiss Capital
extype: schoice
exsolution: 0100000
exshuffle: 5
    </pre>
  </div>
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <b>LaTeX</b>
    <pre>


\exname{Swiss Capital}
\extype{schoice}
\exsolution{0100000}
\exshuffle{5}
    </pre>
  </div>
</div>

<h2 id="numeric-product-rule-for-derivatives">Numeric: Product rule for derivatives</h2>

<p>Arithmetic question for computing the first derivative of a product function with
two factors, using the product rule. The parameters of the function are drawn
randomly in R and subsequently inserted into the question and the solution (which
is not shown below for brevity). LaTeX is used for typesetting the mathematical
formulas - both in the Markdown and the LaTeX version.</p>

<p>To see what the output looks like, run the following code within R or take a look at
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/templates/deriv/">deriv</a> in the exercise gallery.</p>

<div class="row t20 b20">
  <div class="small-5 medium-3 large-2 columns">
    <b>R/Markdown</b><br />
    <img src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/template-rmd.svg" alt="Rmd" />
  </div>
  <div class="small-1 medium-3 large-4 columns">
  <p></p>
  </div>
  <div class="small-5 medium-3 large-2 columns">
    <b>R/LaTeX</b><br />
    <img src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/template-rnw.svg" alt="Rnw" />
  </div>
  <div class="small-1 medium-3 large-4 columns">
  <p></p>
  </div>
</div>

<div class="row t20 b20">
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <pre>
library("exams")
exams2html("deriv.Rmd")
exams2pdf("deriv.Rmd")
    </pre>
  </div>
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <pre>
library("exams")
exams2html("deriv.Rnw")
exams2pdf("deriv.Rnw")
    </pre>
  </div>
</div>

<h4 id="data-generation">Data generation</h4>

<p>The R code simply draws the two parameters <code class="highlighter-rouge">a</code> and <code class="highlighter-rouge">b</code> as well as the argument <code class="highlighter-rouge">c</code>
from a discrete uniform distribution. (See the question below for the actual function used.)
Subsequently, the random numbers are inserted into the correct solution and storing
it as <code class="highlighter-rouge">res</code>.</p>

<div class="row t20 b20">
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <b>R/Markdown</b>
    <pre>
```{r, echo=FALSE, results="hide"}
## parameters
a &lt;- sample(2:9, 1)
b &lt;- sample(seq(2, 4, 0.1), 1)
c &lt;- sample(seq(0.5, 0.8, 0.01), 1)
## solution
res &lt;- exp(b * c) * (a * c^(a-1) +
       b * c^a)
```
    </pre>
  </div>
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <b>R/LaTeX</b>
    <pre>
&lt;&lt;echo=FALSE, results=hide&gt;&gt;=
## parameters
a &lt;- sample(2:9, 1)
b &lt;- sample(seq(2, 4, 0.1), 1)
c &lt;- sample(seq(0.5, 0.8, 0.01), 1)
## solution
res &lt;- exp(b * c) * (a * c^(a-1) +
       b * c^a)
@
    </pre>
  </div>
</div>

<h4 id="question-1">Question</h4>

<p>The question asks for the derivative of a particular function and simply inserts
the parameters drawn above into the question template. (The solution is set up
analogously in the exercise template but not shown here for brevity.)</p>

<div class="row t20 b20">
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <b>R/Markdown</b>
    <pre>
Question
========
What is the derivative of
$f(x) = x^{`r a`} e^{`r b` x}$,
evaluated at $x = `r c`$?
    </pre>
  </div>
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <b>R/LaTeX</b>
    <pre>
\begin{question}
What is the derivative of
$f(x) = x^{\Sexpr{a}} e^{\Sexpr{b}x}$,
evaluated at $x = \Sexpr{c}$?
\end{question}
    </pre>
  </div>
</div>

<h4 id="meta-information-1">Meta-information</h4>

<p>Again, the meta-information lists <code class="highlighter-rouge">extype</code> (which is <code class="highlighter-rouge">num</code> for numeric exercises),
<code class="highlighter-rouge">exsolution</code> (which is inserted dynamically from the variable <code class="highlighter-rouge">res</code> computed above),
and a short <code class="highlighter-rouge">exname</code>. Additionally, the tolerance <code class="highlighter-rouge">extol</code> which is used for automatically
evaluating answers, e.g., in an online test/exam.</p>

<div class="row t20 b20">
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <b>R/Markdown</b>
    <pre>
Meta-information
================
extype: num
exsolution: `r fmt(res)`
exname: derivative exp
extol: 0.01
    </pre>
  </div>
  <div class="medium-6 columns">
    <b>R/LaTeX</b>
    <pre>


\extype{num}
\exsolution{\Sexpr{fmt(res)}}
\exname{derivative exp}
\extol{0.01}
    </pre>
  </div>
</div>

    ]]></description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/first_steps/</guid>
			</item>
		
    
    
			<item>
        <title><![CDATA[Installing R/exams]]></title>
				<link>http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/installation/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <description><![CDATA[
    
    <p>Installation guide for R itself and the R package "exams" as well as further open-source tools that are required for certain tasks.</p>
    
    
    <p><img alt="Installing R/exams" src="http://www.R-exams.org/images/logo.title.svg" /></p>
    
    <h2 id="1-r">1. R</h2>

<p>The R/exams system is an extension for the
<a href="https://www.R-project.org">R system for statistical computing</a> and hence the
first installation step is the base R system.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Windows and (Mac) OS X:</strong> Go to <a href="https://CRAN.R-project.org/">https://CRAN.R-project.org/</a>, the 
 Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN). Simply
 click on the link for your operating system and at least install the “base”
 system. It is recommended to also install the accompanying “Rtools” which are
 not needed immediately but might useful at some stage.</li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Linux:</strong> While it is possible to download from CRAN by hand, it is
easier for most distributions to install the packaged binary. For example,
on Debian/Ubuntu:</p>

    <div class="highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>apt-get install r-base-core r-base-dev
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>There is a wide variety of interfaces for using R including simply the shell,
Emacs, or dedicated graphical user interfaces for Windows and OS X, respectively.
Moreover, RStudio is an open-source cross-platform integrated development
environment that facilitates many common tasks for R beginners.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>For R beginners:</strong> Go to
<a href="https://www.RStudio.com/products/RStudio/">https://www.RStudio.com/products/RStudio/</a> and obtain the “Desktop” version
of RStudio.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="2-r-package-exams">2. R package “exams”</h2>

<p>The core of R/exams is the open-source R package
<a href="https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=exams">“exams”</a>, also available from CRAN.
It can be easily installed interactively from within R with a single command.
If necessary, the development version of the package is also available, which
may provide some new features or small improvements.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Stable version:</strong></p>

    <div class="highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>install.packages("exams", dependencies = TRUE)
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Development version:</strong></p>

    <div class="highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>install.packages("exams", repos = "http://R-Forge.R-project.org")
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><em>Details:</em> Several additional R packages, automatically installed by the command above,
are needed for certain tasks: <code class="highlighter-rouge">base64enc</code> (HTML-based output: Base64 encoding of
supplements), <code class="highlighter-rouge">knitr</code> (R/Markdown-based exercises), <code class="highlighter-rouge">png</code> (NOPS exams: reading
scanned PNG images), <code class="highlighter-rouge">RCurl</code> (ARSnova: posting exercises), <code class="highlighter-rouge">RJSONIO</code> (ARSnova:
JSON format), <code class="highlighter-rouge">rmarkdown</code> (pandoc-based conversion), <code class="highlighter-rouge">tth</code> (HTML output from
R/LaTeX exercises).</p>

<h2 id="3-latex">3. LaTeX</h2>

<p>For producing PDF output, the typesetting system LaTeX is used internally by R/exams.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Windows:</strong> Go to <a href="http://www.MikTeX.org/">http://www.MikTeX.org/</a> and click on “Download” to obtain
the MikTeX distribution for Windows.</li>
  <li><strong>(Mac) OS X and Linux:</strong> LaTeX distributions are available in the standard
repositories and can be installed in the “usual” way, typically using the
<a href="https://www.tug.org/texlive/">TeX Live</a> distribution.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="4-pandoc">4. Pandoc</h2>

<p>For certain conversions performed internally in R/exams, specifically when
Markdown is involved, the universal document converter
<a href="https://www.pandoc.org/">pandoc</a> is employed. If you have installed RStudio, then
pandoc is provided along with it and nothing else needs to be done.</p>

<p>Otherwise pandoc can be obtained from its web page (linked above) or standard repositories,
e.g., for Debian/Ubuntu:</p>

<div class="highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>apt-get install pandoc
</code></pre></div></div>

<h2 id="optional-further-scanning-tools">Optional: Further scanning tools</h2>

<p><em>Note:</em> Unless you want to process <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/intro/written/">written NOPS exams</a>
from scanned PDF files, this section can be skipped.</p>

<p>If the scanned images of written NOPS exams (from your photocopier) are in PDF format,
they need to be converted to PNG first using the PDF Toolkit <code class="highlighter-rouge">pdftk</code> and
ImageMagick’s <code class="highlighter-rouge">convert</code>.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Windows:</strong> Install PDFTk Free, ImageMagick, and Ghostscript.
    <ul>
      <li><a href="http://www.pdflabs.com/tools/pdftk-the-pdf-toolkit/pdftk_free-2.02-win-setup.exe">http://www.pdflabs.com/tools/pdftk-the-pdf-toolkit/pdftk_free-2.02-win-setup.exe</a></li>
      <li><a href="http://www.imagemagick.org/script/download.php#windows">http://www.imagemagick.org/script/download.php#windows</a></li>
      <li><a href="http://www.ghostscript.com/download/gsdnld.html">http://www.ghostscript.com/download/gsdnld.html</a></li>
      <li><em>Note:</em> During the installation of PDFTk and ImageMagick check the boxes for 
“Add application directory to your environmental path” or
“Add application directory to your System Path”, respectively.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>(Mac) OS X:</strong> Install MacPorts, PDFTk Free, and ImageMagick.
    <ul>
      <li><a href="https://www.macports.org/">https://www.macports.org/</a></li>
      <li><a href="https://www.pdflabs.com/tools/pdftk-the-pdf-toolkit/pdftk_server-2.02-mac_osx-10.11-setup.pkg">https://www.pdflabs.com/tools/pdftk-the-pdf-toolkit/pdftk_server-2.02-mac_osx-10.11-setup.pkg</a></li>
      <li><a href="http://www.imagemagick.org/script/download.php#macosx">http://www.imagemagick.org/script/download.php#macosx</a></li>
      <li><em>Note:</em> ImageMagick requires MacPorts which in turn automatically installs Ghostscript as a dependency.
The PDFTk version is for OS X 10.11 up to 10.13 (High Sierra).</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Linux:</strong> Install PDFTk and ImageMagick from your distribution, e.g., for Debian/Ubuntu:</p>

    <div class="highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>apt-get install pdftk imagemagick
</code></pre></div>    </div>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="make-sure-everything-works">Make sure everything works</h2>

<p>To check that the software from Steps 1-4 works, try to run some examples from the
exercise template gallery, e.g., <a href="http://www.R-exams.org/templates/dist">dist</a> or
<a href="http://www.R-exams.org/templates/ttest">ttest</a>.</p>


    ]]></description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.R-exams.org/tutorials/installation/</guid>
			</item>
		
    
    
			<item>
        <title><![CDATA[ttest: Interpretation of 2-Sample t Test]]></title>
				<link>http://www.R-exams.org/templates/ttest/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <description><![CDATA[
    
    <p>Exercise template for assessing the interpretation of a randomly-generated 2-sample t test (including significance and type of alternative).</p>
    
    
    <div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Name:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns"><code class="highlighter-rouge">ttest</code></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Type:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/tag/mchoice/"><code class="highlighter-rouge">mchoice</code></a></div>
</div>

<div class="row t20 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Description:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Results of a 2-sample <code class="highlighter-rouge">t.test()</code> in R need to be interpreted regarding significance, type of alternative, and comparison of the underlying empirical means.</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Solution feedback:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Yes</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Randomization:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Random numbers, text blocks, and R output</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Mathematical notation:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Yes</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Verbatim R input/output:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Yes</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Images:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">No</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Other supplements:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">No</div>
</div>

<div class="row t20 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Template:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-ttest//ttest.Rnw">ttest.Rnw</a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-ttest//ttest.Rmd">ttest.Rmd</a></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Raw:</b> (1 random version)</div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-ttest//ttest.tex">ttest.tex</a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-ttest//ttest.md">ttest.md</a></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>PDF:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-ttest//ttest-Rnw.pdf"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-ttest//ttest-Rnw-pdf.png" alt="ttest-Rnw-pdf" /></a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-ttest//ttest-Rmd.pdf"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-ttest//ttest-Rmd-pdf.png" alt="ttest-Rmd-pdf" /></a></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b20">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>HTML:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-ttest//ttest-Rnw.html"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-ttest//ttest-Rnw-html.png" alt="ttest-Rnw-html" /></a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-ttest//ttest-Rmd.html"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-ttest//ttest-Rmd-html.png" alt="ttest-Rmd-html" /></a></div>
</div>

<p><em>(Note that the HTML output contains mathematical equations in MathML. It is displayed by browsers with MathML support like Firefox or Safari - but not Chrome.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Demo code:</strong></p>

<pre><code class="prettyprint ">library(&quot;exams&quot;)

set.seed(1090)
exams2html(&quot;ttest.Rnw&quot;)
set.seed(1090)
exams2pdf(&quot;ttest.Rnw&quot;)

set.seed(1090)
exams2html(&quot;ttest.Rmd&quot;)
set.seed(1090)
exams2pdf(&quot;ttest.Rmd&quot;)</code></pre>

    ]]></description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.R-exams.org/templates/ttest/</guid>
			</item>
		
    
    
			<item>
        <title><![CDATA[tstat2: 1-Sample t-Test Statistic (Single-Choice)]]></title>
				<link>http://www.R-exams.org/templates/tstat2/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <description><![CDATA[
    
    <p>Exercise template for computing the t-test statistic (single-choice) from given hypothesized mean and empirical mean and variance.</p>
    
    
    <div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Name:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns"><code class="highlighter-rouge">tstat2</code></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Type:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/tag/schoice/"><code class="highlighter-rouge">schoice</code></a></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">   <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Related:</b></div>   <div class="medium-8 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/templates/tstat/"><code class="highlighter-rouge">tstat</code></a></div> </div>

<div class="row t20 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Description:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Computing the 1-sample t-test statistic from randomly-drawn hypothesized mean, sample size, and empirical mean and variance. The correct answer has to be selected from five choice items which have been added to the numeric version of the exercise linked above.</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Solution feedback:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Yes</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Randomization:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Random numbers</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Mathematical notation:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Yes</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Verbatim R input/output:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">No</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Images:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">No</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Other supplements:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">No</div>
</div>

<div class="row t20 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Template:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat2//tstat2.Rnw">tstat2.Rnw</a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat2//tstat2.Rmd">tstat2.Rmd</a></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Raw:</b> (1 random version)</div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat2//tstat2.tex">tstat2.tex</a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat2//tstat2.md">tstat2.md</a></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>PDF:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat2//tstat2-Rnw.pdf"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat2//tstat2-Rnw-pdf.png" alt="tstat2-Rnw-pdf" /></a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat2//tstat2-Rmd.pdf"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat2//tstat2-Rmd-pdf.png" alt="tstat2-Rmd-pdf" /></a></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b20">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>HTML:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat2//tstat2-Rnw.html"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat2//tstat2-Rnw-html.png" alt="tstat2-Rnw-html" /></a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat2//tstat2-Rmd.html"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat2//tstat2-Rmd-html.png" alt="tstat2-Rmd-html" /></a></div>
</div>

<p><em>(Note that the HTML output contains mathematical equations in MathML. It is displayed by browsers with MathML support like Firefox or Safari - but not Chrome.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Demo code:</strong></p>

<pre><code class="prettyprint ">library(&quot;exams&quot;)

set.seed(1090)
exams2html(&quot;tstat2.Rnw&quot;)
set.seed(1090)
exams2pdf(&quot;tstat2.Rnw&quot;)

set.seed(1090)
exams2html(&quot;tstat2.Rmd&quot;)
set.seed(1090)
exams2pdf(&quot;tstat2.Rmd&quot;)</code></pre>

    ]]></description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.R-exams.org/templates/tstat2/</guid>
			</item>
		
    
    
			<item>
        <title><![CDATA[tstat: 1-Sample t-Test Statistic]]></title>
				<link>http://www.R-exams.org/templates/tstat/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <description><![CDATA[
    
    <p>Exercise template for computing the t-test statistic (numeric answer) from given hypothesized mean and empirical mean and variance.</p>
    
    
    <div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Name:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns"><code class="highlighter-rouge">tstat</code></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Type:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/tag/num/"><code class="highlighter-rouge">num</code></a></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">   <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Related:</b></div>   <div class="medium-8 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/templates/tstat2/"><code class="highlighter-rouge">tstat2</code></a></div> </div>

<div class="row t20 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Description:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Computing the 1-sample t-test statistic from randomly-drawn hypothesized mean, sample size, and empirical mean and variance.</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Solution feedback:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Yes</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Randomization:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Random numbers</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Mathematical notation:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Yes</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Verbatim R input/output:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">No</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Images:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">No</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Other supplements:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">No</div>
</div>

<div class="row t20 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Template:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat//tstat.Rnw">tstat.Rnw</a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat//tstat.Rmd">tstat.Rmd</a></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Raw:</b> (1 random version)</div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat//tstat.tex">tstat.tex</a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat//tstat.md">tstat.md</a></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>PDF:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat//tstat-Rnw.pdf"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat//tstat-Rnw-pdf.png" alt="tstat-Rnw-pdf" /></a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat//tstat-Rmd.pdf"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat//tstat-Rmd-pdf.png" alt="tstat-Rmd-pdf" /></a></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b20">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>HTML:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat//tstat-Rnw.html"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat//tstat-Rnw-html.png" alt="tstat-Rnw-html" /></a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat//tstat-Rmd.html"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-tstat//tstat-Rmd-html.png" alt="tstat-Rmd-html" /></a></div>
</div>

<p><em>(Note that the HTML output contains mathematical equations in MathML. It is displayed by browsers with MathML support like Firefox or Safari - but not Chrome.)</em></p>

<p><strong>Demo code:</strong></p>

<pre><code class="prettyprint ">library(&quot;exams&quot;)

set.seed(1090)
exams2html(&quot;tstat.Rnw&quot;)
set.seed(1090)
exams2pdf(&quot;tstat.Rnw&quot;)

set.seed(1090)
exams2html(&quot;tstat.Rmd&quot;)
set.seed(1090)
exams2pdf(&quot;tstat.Rmd&quot;)</code></pre>

    ]]></description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.R-exams.org/templates/tstat/</guid>
			</item>
		
    
    
			<item>
        <title><![CDATA[switzerland: Knowledge Quiz Question about Switzerland]]></title>
				<link>http://www.R-exams.org/templates/switzerland/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <description><![CDATA[
    
    <p>Exercise template for a multiple-choice knowledge quiz question with basic shuffling of the alternatives.</p>
    
    
    <div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Name:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns"><code class="highlighter-rouge">switzerland</code></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Type:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/tag/mchoice/"><code class="highlighter-rouge">mchoice</code></a></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">   <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Related:</b></div>   <div class="medium-8 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/templates/swisscapital/"><code class="highlighter-rouge">swisscapital</code></a></div> </div>

<div class="row t20 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Description:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Knowledge quiz question (about Switzerland) with 2 correct and 3 false alternatives which are shuffled randomly in each version of the exercise.</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Solution feedback:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Yes</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Randomization:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">Shuffling</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Mathematical notation:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">No</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Verbatim R input/output:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">No</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Images:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">No</div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Other supplements:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-8 columns">No</div>
</div>

<div class="row t20 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Template:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-switzerland//switzerland.Rnw">switzerland.Rnw</a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-switzerland//switzerland.Rmd">switzerland.Rmd</a></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>Raw:</b> (1 random version)</div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-switzerland//switzerland.tex">switzerland.tex</a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-switzerland//switzerland.md">switzerland.md</a></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b1">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>PDF:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-switzerland//switzerland-Rnw.pdf"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-switzerland//switzerland-Rnw-pdf.png" alt="switzerland-Rnw-pdf" /></a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-switzerland//switzerland-Rmd.pdf"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-switzerland//switzerland-Rmd-pdf.png" alt="switzerland-Rmd-pdf" /></a></div>
</div>
<div class="row t1 b20">
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><b>HTML:</b></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-switzerland//switzerland-Rnw.html"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-switzerland//switzerland-Rnw-html.png" alt="switzerland-Rnw-html" /></a></div>
  <div class="medium-4 columns"><a href="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-switzerland//switzerland-Rmd.html"><img src="http://www.R-exams.org/assets/posts/2017-08-14-switzerland//switzerland-Rmd-html.png" alt="switzerland-Rmd-html" /></a></div>
</div>

<p><strong>Demo code:</strong></p>

<pre><code class="prettyprint ">library(&quot;exams&quot;)

set.seed(1090)
exams2html(&quot;switzerland.Rnw&quot;)
set.seed(1090)
exams2pdf(&quot;switzerland.Rnw&quot;)

set.seed(1090)
exams2html(&quot;switzerland.Rmd&quot;)
set.seed(1090)
exams2pdf(&quot;switzerland.Rmd&quot;)</code></pre>

    ]]></description>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.R-exams.org/templates/switzerland/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
